■
翻译：圣城家园SCG-CMCT团队
校对：JohnJackson监制：L.C.后期：JohnJackson
地心毁灭
世界环保日  波士顿
我的表停了
It stopped.
怎么了  大卫
What's that, Dave?
没什么
Nothing.
准备得怎么样
How we doing?
哦  准备好了
Oh, we're ready.
你有信心吗
You feeling the magic?
有  我信心十足  很好
Oh, I'm feeling the magic, all right.
我们去说服他们
Let's hit them.
好啊
Yeah.
走吧
Let's do it.
走
Here we go.
我们去说服他们
Let's hit them.
我们要拿到这３千万
Let's go make $30 million.
大家好
Good morning.
开始之前  让我…
Before I begin, let me...
大卫
David?
我去叫人来
I'll go get help.
天呐  大卫
Jesus. Jesus, David.
快打911  快打911
Phone 9-1-1. Phone 9-1-1!
大卫
David?
尼克
Nick?
尼克  尼克
Nicky?Nicky!
好了  没事了
Okay, it's okay.
没事了
It's okay.
所有人都从车上下来
Everybody else off the bus.
声波
Sound waves.
我们知道当声波
So, if we know that sound waves
穿越越来越多的障碍物后
gain wavelength and lose frequency
它的波长增加而频率减少
as they travel through more dense materials...
我们就可以据此确定声场中
...then the anomalies in these waves
不规则物体的形状和位置
are the means by which we can surmise
据此我们也可以分析地球的构造
the fundamental architecture of our planet.
克丽丝汀  你的指甲怎么了
How are the nails coming, Christine?
很好
Good.
下面  让我们来做个示范
All right, let's have a demonstration.
艾克先生 维罗妮卡  麻烦你们
Mr. Acker, Veronica.
十分感谢
Thank you very much.
好的
All right.
你们知道  莱仕东夫人很大但也很柔软
Mrs. Limestone, being a big softie, you know,
喜欢在公园散步  听枕边故事
Ioves walks in the park, bedtime stories,
很浪漫的那种
big romantic.
喜欢甜言蜜语
Loves Chet.
我不懂甜言蜜语 但我来看看能做些什么
I can't play Chet, but I'll see what I can do.
盯着示波器  好了吗
Watch the oscilloscope, all right?
仔细看着
Here we go.
约书亚·凯斯博士
Dr. Joshua Keyes?
也许
Maybe.
是还是不是
Yes or no, sir?
是
The first one.
先生  请跟我们来
Please come with us, sir.
伙计们出了什么事
Guys, wh-what's going on?
我们也不知道  先生
We don't know, sir.
你说什么  你们也不知道
What do you mean, you don't know?
您的忠诚调查评价比我们要高
Your security clearance is higher than ours.
我做过忠诚调查
I have security clearance?
我们一到您的飞机那儿去
We're just here to bring you to your jet.
我有飞机
I have a jet?
华盛顿特区
你好  赛吉
Hey, Serge.
-赛吉  赛吉  -妈的
-Serge Serge -Damn!
到时间了．你总是迟到
It's about time. You're always late.
走吧  先生们
Let's keep moving, gentlemen.
要我来这里干什么啊
What am I doing here?
在你来到之前  他们都不给我说
They wouldn't brief me until you got here.
这里到处都是军方的生物化学工作者
You know, there are biochemists everywhere, military.
我讨厌他们
I hate them.
你什么时候能找到个好女孩
When are you going to meet a nice girl
和她一起共进晚餐呢
and bring her for dinner?
我几经和我的工作结婚了
I'm married to my work.
我也是
So am l.
她既是妻子又是情人
Which makes my wife my mistress...
所以我深爱着她
that's why I'm still in love with her.
你总是这么浪漫啊
You were always a romantic.
我爱我的妻子
I love my wife.
是的．我也很爱你的妻子
Yeah, I know. I love your wife, too.
我明白
I know.
但我并不爱你的那个妻子 你知道我在说什么
But I don't love your wife. You know what I mean.
你爱她的方式和我不一样  你知道的
You don't love her the same way, you know.
这是个法国式的笑话
It's the French. I think it's the cheese.
法式的
The cheese.
你在…你在考我吗
You're... you're teasing me, right?
噢  天
Oh, my...!
这些是尸体
Wait, these are bodies.
我们是不是来错地方了
I think we're in the wrong place here.
我们应该是走错地方了
Yeah, we're in the wrong place.
不  如果你们真的走错了地方
No. If you were in the wrong place,
早就打死了
you would've already been shot.
真是个疯狂的问候啊
That's a hell of a greeting.
赛吉
Serge.
是的  赛吉  很荣幸见到你
Serge. Yes. Always a pleasure.
很荣幸  托马斯
Same here, Thomas.
凯斯  博士
Dr. Keyes.
-我知道  -汤姆·珀塞尔
-I know. -Tom Purcell.
先生们  我想你们已经知道
Gentlemen, you do realize that everything here
这里的一切都是顶极机密的
is totally classified, okay?
在当地时间早上10点30分
At 10:30 a.m. Iocal time,
在10个街区的范围内  32个市民
32 civilians, all within a 10-block radius...
都死了
died.
他们在之前并没有生病
They didn't get sick first.
他们很简单得倒在地上死了
They simply hit the ground dead.
没有别的原因
Nerve agent?
我们的初步猜测是…  没有
Our first guess. No.
他们是在同一时间死掉的
They all died at the same time?
据我们的调查结果  就是在同一时间
As far as we can tell, to the second.
这件事一小时之内就震动了美国有线新闻网络
This hits CNN in one hour.
我需要答案
I need a reason.
在性别  年龄或者身体特征方面产生了什么变异吗
Is there a variation in sex, age, body type?
他们都安装了内置的心脏起搏器
They all had pacemakers.
一分钟之内就反应过来
Under a minute.
真是名不虚传
Your reputation is well deserved.
在没有检查过受害者之前
How did you guess?
你是怎么猜到的
Without any clues from the victims?
不…
No, that's...
赛吉和我就是线索吧
Serge and I are the clues.
我是说  他精通的是高能量武器
I mean, he specializes in high energy weapons.
而我是地磁方面的专家
I do geomagnetics.
叫我们来  就是说你们怀疑
So calling us means you suspect
这是一种电磁脉冲武器
an electromagnetic pulse weapon.
如果这只是天灾
If these are the only fatalities,
他们一定是很容易
they must be people susceptible to...
受电磁波影响的人
electronic interference.
QED型心脏起搏器
QED pacemakers.
有时候你真像鬼一样精明
You're spooky sometimes, eh?
我想知道的是
Now I need to know,
这些人被一种武器所杀的可能性有多大
did some sort of weapon kill these people?
要造成足够强度的EM脉冲
The power that you would need
所需要的能量…
to create an EM pulse strong enough...
我是说  我从没听说过这样一种武器
I mean, that's... that's not a weapon thatI've ever heard of.
没有
No.
好的  我们的工作完成了
Okay, we're done.
还没有完啊  先生
We're not done, sir.
等号的另一边还是空的
There's nothing on the other side of the equal sign.
我同意约书亚说的
I agree with Joshua...
谢谢你们
Thank you.
我们最关心的是这次事件是不是一场军事袭击
Our greatest concern was this may have been an act of war,
现在确认它不是
but since it's not,
我想我们可以放轻松一些了  不是吗
I think we can all breathe a little easier, can't we?
伦敦  特拉法尔加广场
看我的帽子
Look at my hat.
怎么了  亲爱的
What is it, sweetheart?
这没什么  儿子
It's okay, son.
这种事情每时每刻都在发生 并且…
These things happen all the time and...
快走
Let's, go, let's go! Come on!
贾斯廷
Justin!
看着点  你这白痴
Watch out, you bloody idiot!
快啊  快跑
Hurry! Run!
爸爸
Daddy!
现在  纳尔逊广场的上空一无所有
The skies are empty over Nelson's Column now,
但就在几个小时之前  又是不同的情景
but a few hours ago, it was a different story.
目击者声称狂乱的鸟群
Eyewitnesses claimed that the frenzied swarms of birds
并不是在有意攻击人类
were not in fact attacking people deliberately.
并不是只有这一次  不不不不不
And it's not just this time. No, no, no, no, no, no.
而是看上去毫无目的盲目的乱飞
but seemed to be confused and flying blind.
这本杂志上报道过类似的事件
The Fortean Times reported violent bird swarms
上个月在澳大利亚和日本出现过2次狂乱的鸟群
twice last month in Australia and Japan.
（据证实已有5人死亡上百人受伤）
(Five people are confirmed dead and dozens injured)
（在惊恐之后是巨大的疑问  不久之后同样的事件发生在）
(in the panic that followed the bizarre and terrifying incident)
（伦敦著名的特拉法尔加广场）
(in London's historic T rafalgar Square.)
真是怪异
Weird.
这也太奇怪了
Quite strange, also.
确实很奇怪
Strange, indeed.
鸟类是怎样辨认方向的
How do birds navigate?
靠视力
By sight?
不不不  我是说在长距离迁徙时
No, no, no, the long range stuff.
地磁力场
Magnetic fields.
他们的脑子里有一种
Little ions in their brains
与地磁力场相关的微小粒子
align with the magnetic field of the Earth.
-对  就是她说的  -对吗
-Yeah, what she said. -Right?
涡流
Acker.
我们到网上  找找…
Hit the 'Net, do a search for...
噢  2年内的
oh, two years ought to do it.
所有的超自然事件的新闻  主要是关于
Any and all, like, "weird news", you know...
奇异的动物迁徙
bizarre animal migrations,
尤其是鸟类
specifically birds.
鲸鱼和海豚的海滩搁浅
Whale and dolphin beachings.
不正常的大气现象  原因不明的飞机坠毁
Unusual atmospheric phenomenon, unexplained plane crashes,
发挥你的想象力
you know, just use your imagination.
这个查找可是工作量巨大啊
That is a huge search.
你能用我们的T1专线来看《水手月》  废物
You can use our T-1 line to look up Sailor Moon crap.
你也只能干这个了
You're up to this.
唐丹妮 唐丹妮
Danni, Danni
帮我在“场论”专业的班级里
get me the brightest kids
找几个最聪明小子来
from the Field Theory Class,
帮我设计个电磁场的模型
and design a computer model of an electromagnetic field.
我们该干些什么
What are we doing?
我需要一个地球的立体模型
I need a 3-D computer model of the Earth
来放置这个磁场模型
to lay the field over.
地球的
the planet Earth?
是的  地球的  就是那个漂亮的蓝色星球
Yeah, the planet Earth. You know, the pretty blue one.
在地图上标出找到的不规则的涡流
Map out the anomalies that Acker finds
并构造出方程式
and grunt out the equations.
并且
And
去找一些研究非线性理论的
grab those smelly kids
班级里那些臭烘烘小子来
from the Non-Linear Diff class, too.
听我说约书亚  我们还有时间干这些吗
Listen, Josh, do we even have time for this?
老老实实给我干活  你的博士学位就没问题了
Do this and I'll sign your doctorates blindfolded.
-快到手了  -是的
-Blindfolded? -Blindfolded.
不用考试  直接拿到博士学位
Do not pass Go. Go directly to PhD.
但愿是我错了  但愿是我错了
Be wrong. Be wrong.
蒂姆  我有些紧张
Tim, I'm coming in a little hot.
能帮我一下吗
Give me some drag, will you?
行啊
Roger that.
我们已经调整好进入入射界面角度
We are in attitude and ready for an entry interface.
做的好  少校
Nice work, Major.
我接手控制了
I have the controls now for E.I.
交给我好了
I could take us in.
你能够…
You could...
但你不可以
but you won't.
我已经做好准备了
I'm ready for this, Bob.
不  小贝你没有
No, you're not, Beck.
虽然你受过这方面的训练而且也是合格的
You're trained, and you're certified
但别把自己当作指挥官
doesn't make you the commander.
你现在还没有资格指挥着陆行动
And the commander lands the bird.
你应该是进入太空的人当中最年轻的了
You got to be the youngest person ever in space.
你应该说“谢谢” 开心点吧
You should say, thank you, be happy.
现在
Now.
艾德华号  这里是休斯敦基地
Endeavour, Houston, at this time
现在给你们导航
We show you go for reentry.
休斯敦基地  艾德华号的距离缩短到400 000英尺
Houston, Endeavour descending through 400, 000 feet
就要到达进入面
coming upon entry interface.
艾德华号  这是弗莱特
Endeavour, this is Flight.
这次又没有说服指挥官
Weren't able to annoy the commander
让你驾驶着陆吧
into letting you bring her in this time?
确实是没有  史迪克
That's a negative, Stick.
下次我一定要多给他找点麻烦
I'll have to be more annoying next time.
你认为这有用吗
Is that even possible?
艾德华号
Endeavour,
我们看见你进来了  调整得很好
we see you in good entry config.
收到  休斯敦
Roger, Houston.
警告
Advise.
我看见一片等离子区域
I'm seeing those plasma trails now.
好的  标记为24  1/2
All right, mark 24 1/2.
还有一分钟接触大气层
So, a minute to air.
我不相信安全带
I don't believe in belts.
只要这艘船能带我穿越大气层
Just get me through the Earth's atmosphere in this spaceship.
信号丢失
Com dropout.
开始接收
Start the I Com.
我们等到…
Let's wait till the...
信号恢复
Com restored.
警告  偏离轨道
安静
Quiet!
我们偏离航向了
We are out of position here.
领航系统显示我们在正确的位置上
Guidance shows us on energy and on course.
我在模拟训练中走过213次这条路线
Well, I've made this approach 213 times in the simulator.
我们不应该在这
We're not where we should be.
我们到底在哪里
Where the hell are we?
艾德华号  领航系统故障了
Endeavour, guidance is bad.
你们偏离航道102英里
You are now 1-2-niner miles off course.
收到  休斯敦基地 我们多少也注意到了
Roger, Houston. We sort of noticed.
那里是…
Is that...?
洛杉矶  这点可以确定
Los Angeles. That is confirmed.
我们的高度只有105 000英尺了
We are 1-5 thousand feet.
我们只剩下2分钟
We got maybe two minutes of glide time left.
说这些都是无意义的
Doesn't make sense.
领航和灯塔系统都坏了吗
The guidance, the beacons are all wrong?
我们正笔直地飞向市区
We're heading straight for downtown.
我们不能撞击洛杉矶啊
We're not going to crash into Los Angeles.
他们会以300节的速度
They're going to hit downtown L.A.
撞击洛杉矶
at 300 knots.
鲍勃  你知道洛杉矶吗  我有个主意
Bob, you know L.A.? Because I have an idea.
休斯敦基地  那些建筑物越来越大了
Houston, those buildings are getting mighty big.
你们能清理出一条高速公路吗
Can you clear a freeway?
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
快呀  快呀
Come on. Come on.
现在是繁忙时间  指挥官
It's rush hour, Commander,
路上的车一辆接一辆的
and it's bumper-to-bumper.
长官  我有个替代方案
Sir, I have an alternate.
如果你朝向10705…
If you turn to heading 1-7-5...
呼叫休斯敦基地  休斯敦
It's Houston's call. Houston?
计算机还在测绘
Computers are still plotting.
快呀
Come on.
休斯敦
Houston, we are running
我们没多少时间了
out of time here.
长官  我有个替代方案
Sir, I have an alternate.
好吧  小贝  你想说什么
All right, Beck, what do you got?
休斯敦  我找到个
Houston, I have coordinates
替代的降落地点
for an alternate landing site.
你能批准吗
Can you confirm?
艾德华号  把资料给我
Endeavour, give them to me.
我找到的地点是北纬33.55  西经118.10
I show possible touchdown... at 33.55 north, 118.10 west.
比尔
Bill?
理论上是可以的
It's theoretically possible.
艾德华号
Endeavour,
提案批准
that is confirmed.
右转  航向10705
T urn right, heading 1-7-5.
5秒之内和洛杉矶河
Expect visual contact
来一次亲密接触吧
with Los Angeles River in five seconds.
不  休斯敦基地  这行不通
No, that will not work, Houston.
每隔几百米就有一座桥
We got bridges every few hundred yards.
我们会死的
Our wingspan alone is going to fold us up.
我已经演算过了
I've figured the "L" over "D" max.
可以做得到  只要你带我们直直的飞过去
We can make it if you can bring us straight in.
太疯狂了
We're coming in high and hot.
290英尺  320节
290 feet, 320.
放下轮子
-270, 3-0-5... -Arm the gear.
启动完成
You're armed.
放下起落架
Gear down. Now.
放下了
Gear in transition.
240英尺  290节
240 feet, 290.
坚持住  现在需要精确的控制
Hang on. This isn't going to be subtle.
210英尺  265节
210 feet, 265.
离开路面  快跑
Get out of the way! Move!
反旋
Derotate.
向内
Inward.
230…210…
230...210...
紧急刹车
Speed brakes!
100%启动
100%.
我们太快了
We're way too fast.
展开侧斜翼
Deploy the chute.
不  会撞上桥的 我们从下面穿过去
No. We'd snag the bridge. We'll tear the tail off.
向右转
Banking right.
指挥官  下一座桥
Commander, that next bridge!
注意
Watch it!
我们太高了
We're way too high for that one!
收起轮子
Suck up the gear!
现在还不行  我们会失去控制的
Not yet. We'll lose all steering.
如果撞上了  就都完了
We hit, it's over!
现在…收起轮子
And... gear up now!
抓紧了  现在我没法控制它了
Lock your harnesses. This is out of my hands.
快离开这里
Let's get out of here!
跑啊  快跑
Run! Let's get out!
自然科学学院
康拉德辛斯基博士
辛斯基博士
Dr. Zimsky?!
你能把电话号码留给我的助手吗  亲爱的
Will you make sure my assistant has your number, darling?
好的
Sure.
辛斯基博士
Dr. Zimsky!
不  这很好  这很好．你好
No, it's all right. It's all right. Hello.
-辛斯基博士  -是的  你叫什么
-Dr. Zimsky. -Yes. What's your name?
-约书亚·凯斯  -约书亚
-Josh Keyes. -Josh.
不先生  我不是来要你得签名的
No, sir, I don't need you to sign it.
我要你读一下这个
I need you to read that.
对不起  我没有时间
I'm sorry, I don't have time.
白宫的会议我已经迟到了
I'm late for the White House.
我需要你来确定我的研究发现
I need you to confirm my results, sir.
年轻人  你知道我是谁吗
Young man, do you have any idea who I am?
是的先生  请你读一下这个
Yes, I do, sir. Please read this.
这是什么
What's it about?
世界的末日
It's the end of the world.
不  我想…  这不可能  对不起
No, l... this is impossible. I'm sorry.
我  我  我不会错过这些现象的
I-l-I can't have missed this.
你一定是错了
You-You have to be wrong.
我是说  我很肯定
I mean, look, I'm sure
仔细地和我的研究结论对比一下
with careful comparison to my own work,
很明显你搞错了
we'll find that you are mistaken.
不需要争辨  但是…
No offense, but...
我的意思是  我们很快就会了解的
Well, I mean, we'll know soon enough.
现在  还有好多怪异的现象会发生
The bigger effects will start up any day now.
机密文件
蕾贝卡
Rebecca?
只有你和父亲还在这么叫我
Only you and Dad ever call me that.
好吧  小贝
Well, Beck.
你怎么到华盛顿来了
So, what brings you to sunny D.C.?
下周就是飞行评测了
The Board of Review is next week.
我想探听一下上面的意思
Just trying to get a sense of the mood upstairs.
有多糟糕
How bad is it?
你们撞毁了那架航天飞机
Your crew crashed the space shuttle.
他们的心情还能好到哪去
Now, how good do you think it could be?
先生  这是我的生命
Sir, this is my life.
是吗…
Well...
我13岁开始  就在专门的学校学习
I was studying for the academy when I was 1 3.
这就是我的生命啊
It still is and has always been my life.
结束了
It's over.
结束了  蕾贝卡
It's over, Rebecca.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
就发生在下面
It's right down here.
真的
Really?
那就好像7月14的焰火
It's like the 4th of July.
这怎么这么繁忙啊
What the hell's the hurry here?
蕾贝卡  我能离开一下吗
Rebecca, would you excuse me, please?
对不起
Excuse me.
珀塞尔
Purcell.
托马斯
Thomas, um, look...
命运真是捉弄人
It seems that destiny may have caught up with us.
辛斯基真的要给你他的亲笔签名
Did Zimsky really try to give you his autograph?
啊  辛斯基先生
Ah, Monsieur Zimsky.
康拉德·辛斯基
Conrad Zimsky.
辛斯基先生
Herr Zimsky.
超级明星
Superstar.
我以为我已经戒酒了
I think I skipped drunk.
喝醉的滋味可不好受
Went right to hangover.
你不也是吗
Weren't you the one?
我和孩子们聊过了
I spoke with the kids.
他们现在晚上都不睡觉了
They don't sleep at night.
他们看着天空  并且…他们认为这样很美
They look at the sky, and... and they think it's pretty.
不会是你弄错了吧
Is there any chance you're wrong?
不  天空  伙计
No. The sky, man.
我是说  天空变成这样只是个开始
The sky-- I mean, that's just the beginning.
那是高层空间的静电放电效果
That's high-altitude static discharge.
我知道
I know.
凯斯博士…
Dr. Keyes...
…你必须出席在五角大楼召开的会议
...your presence is required at the Pentagon.
原来是我军方的老朋友啊
It's my best buddies.
为什么不来和我们一起喝一杯呢
Why don't you join us for a drink?
如果你随我们来的话我们将不胜感激  先生
We'd be grateful if you could join us for a ride, sir.
如果我说不呢
And if I were to say no?
就问问
Just asking.
这个…我们没有幽默感
Well, we have no sense of humor.
这倒是真的
That's true.
但我们有枪
And we're armed.
谢谢
Thank you.
欢迎你  凯斯博士
Dr. Keyes, welcome.
谢谢
Thank you.
辛斯基博士告诉我们
Dr. Zimsky informs us
你为他的研究做出了有用的贡献
that you made a useful contribution
所以他希望你
to his investigations, so he wanted you
来做他报告的助手
to assist him in the briefing.
你可真是慷慨啊  辛斯基博士
That's very generous of you, Dr. Zimsky.
小伙子  科学是无私的事业
Science is a selfless business, dear boy.
现在  为什么不开始呢
Now, why don't you begin,
我会在一些难点上加以解释的
and I'll fill in all the difficult bits.
好的  我会尽量的说得简单一些
All right, I'll put this as simply as I can.
一年之内地球上所有的人都会死掉
Everybody on Earth is dead in a year.
让我来解释为什么
And let me explain why.
我们的地球是被一种无形的能量包裹着的
Wrapped around the Earth is an invisible field of energy.
它由电荷与磁力构成
It's made up of... electricity and magnetism,
所以它被称为
so it's called creatively enough
电磁场
the electromagnetic field.
这也就是北磁极和南磁极的成因
It's where we get our magnetic North Pole and South Pole,
并且它还保护我们不受宇宙射线的伤害
and it protects us from cosmic radiation.
所以这个磁场是我们的朋友
So this EM field is our friend.
但是现在呢
But now...?
但是现在  这个场正在分裂
But now, that field is falling apart.
为什么
Why?
在这里
This here.
谁能给我找一罐空气清新剂
Does somebody have a can of air freshener?
我会尽量简明些
Quick and dirty.
这层薄薄的皮  就是地球的表面
The thin skin, that's the Earth's crust.
也就是我们生活的地方
That's what we live on.
它有30英里厚
It's 30 miles thick.
果肉部分  可以称之为地幔
The meat here, call it the mantle.
别管它们的过渡部分
And forgetting all the-the funky transitions,
他有2000英里厚
it's 2, 000 miles thick.
这个核心
The core,
中间突出来的部分  是最狡猾的部分
the peach pit in the center... that's a tricky one.
它由2部分构成
There's two parts
内核和外核
the inner core and the outer core.
明白吗
Are you following me?
这个内核
The inner core
是…
is, uh...
我们认为它是
well, it's a big, solid chunk of iron,
巨大滚烫的固体
we think.
它被外核所包围
And that's surrounded
外核是流体形式的
by the outer core, and that is liquid.
是的  但是
Yes, but,
最重要的是
most importantly, this liquid is constantly spinning
这些流体始终是向一个方向流动的
in one direction.
上万亿吨的滚烫的溶态金属
So a trillion trillion tons of hot metal
以上千英里的时速流动着  所以…
spinning at a thousand miles an hour, so...
是的  物理学上
Right, so Physics 101
热金属的快速移动会形成电磁场
hot metal moving fast makes an electromagnetic field.
流动的外核就是发动机
This spinning liquid outer core is the engine
它驱动着地磁场
that drives the EM Field.
这也就是出问题的地方
And that's where we have our problem.
这个发动机停止运转了
This engine has stalled.
地核停止运动了
The core of the Earth has stopped spinning.
怎么会发生这种事情
How could this have happened?
我们不知道
We don't know.
我们还有多少时间
What's the timeline here?
电磁场变得越来越不稳定
As the EM Field becomes more and more unstable,
会附带着发生些意外
we'll start seeing isolated incidents.
一架飞机从天上掉下来
One plane will fall from the sky,
之后是第二架  然后…
and then two, and then...
几个月之内  任何东西
in a few months, anything...
所有电子设备都将瘫痪
everything electronic will be fried.
空气中的静电释放
Static discharges in the atmosphere
会造成一场闪电风暴  每平方英里
will create "super-storms" with hundreds
会遭到数百道闪电的的轰击
of lightening strikes per square mile.
在那之后更加糟糕
After that, it gets bad.
地球的电磁场保护我们不受
The Earth's EM Field
太阳风当中致命的辐射粒子
shields us from the solar winds, which are a lethal blend
和微波的伤害
of radioactive particles and microwaves.
当这层装甲崩溃了  微波辐射
When that shield collapses, microwave radiation
会直接的
will literally
烘烤我们的地球
cook our planet.
辛斯基博士
Dr. Zimsky.
这个就是太阳
This is the Sun.
这个就是地球…没有了电磁场的保护
This is the Earth... without the EM Field.
能帮个手吗
Would you?
3个月后  我们就回到石器时代了
Three months, gentlemen, and we're back in the Stone Age.
一年之后  磁场会崩塌
A full year, the field collapses...
就象这样
and that.
可以吗
May l?
可以扔掉了
Feel free to throw up. I know I did.
那么  我们该做些什么
So, how do we fix it?
什么也做不了
We can't.
在我的字典里没有不可能
Not in my vocabulary.
那你可能要加进去这个词了  将军
Then you might want to get one of those
因为
Word-A-Day calendars, General, because
这是不可能的
it's impossible.
地核有火星那么大
The core is the size of Mars.
我在说的是要进入行星
You're talking about jump-starting a planet.
它是滚烫的流体
This is a superheated hyper-fluid
足有9 000华氏度
of molten iron and nickel at 9, 000 degrees Fahrenheit,
2 000英里之下  1 000英里厚
2, 000 miles down, 1, 000 miles thick.
而我们到过的最深的地方只有…7英里
And the deepest we've ever been is... seven miles
用了2英寸大的钻头
with a two-inch drill bit.
如果我们能进入太空  我们当然也能…
If we can go into space, we certainly...
进入太空是比较简单的
Well, space is easy.
因为它是空的
It's empty.
我们在说的是
We're talking about millions of pounds
每平方英寸上百万磅的压力
of pressure per square inch.
就算我们想到了绝妙的解决方案
Even if we somehow came up with a brilliant plan
来拯救地核  我们该怎么样到那里呢
to fix the core, we just can't get there.
是的  但是…
Yes, but...
…如果我们真的可以呢
...what if we could?
犹他州  盐带平地
你好  布雷兹
Hello, Braz.
你他妈的怎么还没死呢
Why the hell aren't you dead yet?
好的  走这边
Okay, this way.
比我预料的要好
Well, that went better than I expected.
布雷兹博士  我知道你认识辛斯基博士
Dr. Brazzleton, I see you know Dr. Zimsky.
20年前  他窃取了我的研究成果
20 years ago, he stole my research.
在那之后我们就没有接触过了
After that, we-we kind of lost touch.
那项研究也是属于我的
Research that was equally mine.
真有趣  因为我不记得有任何
That's funny, I don't remember a check
专利局的证据
from any of the patents.
好了  布雷兹
All right, Braz.
20年的沙漠生活  使你成了个愤世嫉俗的家伙
20 years in the desert makes you a prophet and a martyr.
我们来这里是来看你那条神奇的船的
Look, we're here about your legendary ship.
好的  那是我将高频率脉冲激光
Okay, I'm combining high-frequency pulse lasers
和超声波共鸣管相结合的产物．
with resonance tube ultrasonics.
如果你们在探索节目看见过
If you've ever seen ultrasonic waves
超声波粉碎肾结石的话
break up a kidney stone on the Discovery Channel,
它们的原理是一样的
it's the same deal here.
请把头盔戴上
You can... put your helmets on now.
点火
Firing.
很好  令人印象深刻
Okay, I'm officially impressed.
好
So, all right.
看来你对引擎做了不少的改进啊
So you've made some progress
我们承认你的贡献
with the engine, we'll grant you.
你有没有考虑过它的外壳
Have you begun to think about a shell?
好的  这个是亚历克斯．
Okay, this is Alex.
好的  亚历克斯  很好
Okay, Alex. Good.
下面是混凝土块
Okay, here we have a concrete block,
后边是2英寸厚的钢板
and in back of that, we have a two-inch steel plate.
我们准备好了
Okay. We're ready.
然后…点火
And we are... firing.
瞧
Voila!
这真是…
That's...
真是不可思议
That's impossible.
我在超低温下
I combined the crystals
在结晶中混合了钨的结构
in a tungsten-titanium matrix at supercool temperatures,
产生了这种效果
and that's what did the trick.
关于具体的制造工艺还是…
The applications for this are just...
你怎么称呼这种材料
What do you call this material?
哦  他的学名由37个音节构成
Well, its real name has 37 syllables.
我叫它Unobtainium
I call it Unobtainium.
Unobtainium
Unobtainium?
对
Mm-hmm.
Unobtainium会吸收压力和热量
The Unobtainium will take the heat and the pressure
并把它们转化为能量
and transform it to energy,
船的外壳就是由它构成的
which in turn, reinforces the shell of the ship, you see.
所以在理论上来说  她到达得越深  所处的地方越热
So the hotter and the deeper she gets,
她就越强劲有力
the stronger she gets... theoretically.
理论上来说
Theoretically?
理论上  是的
Theoretically, yes.
这是约翰逊  别理他
This... is Johnson, don't mind him.
这是驾驶舱的原型
This is the prototype for the cockpit here.
打断一下  布雷兹博士
Excuse me, Dr. Brazzleton,
这艘船什么时候可以用
when do you think the ship will be operational?
如果找到了完美的装配方案…
When I get my fabrication methods perfected...
12不…10年  10年就可以
12... 10 years, 10 years.
如果要让她在3个月内准备好要多少钱
What would it take to get it done in three months?
150亿…
$15 billion. I...
你能再具体核对一下吗
Will you take a check?
你为什么不用信用卡付帐
Why don't you use a credit card? You get miles.
妈的
Shit!
芬奇先生  我们是联邦调查局的  我们被授权来
Mr. Finch, this is the FBl. We have a warrant.
删除
Purge!
快  删除
Come on, purge!
FBI  不许动
FBl! Freeze!
好的．
Okay.
我知道这些东西看上去像电脑
I know these look like computers.
但完全不是那么回事
Totally not.
希欧多尔·唐纳德·芬奇
Theodore Donald Finch.
卡内基梅隆大学  麻省理工学院
Carnegie-Mellon University. M.I.T.
曾在SUN公司  朗讯公司  兰德公司工作过
Worked at the Sun, Lucent, Rand Corp.
我的外号是“老鼠”  叫我老鼠
My handle's "Rat." Call me Rat.
63项计算机欺诈指控
63 computer fraud indictments.
是64项
64.
2项被定罪
Two convictions.
马上就会增加到3项了
This is strike three, Mr. Finch.
等等
Wait a second.
你们这些人来这里不是只为了要收拾我吧
You guys aren't here to whack me, are you?
因为在那发生之前我真的想
Because I was really, really hoping to have sex
有一次性经验
before that happened.
是的  FBI已经告诉我  去年
Yeah. I've been told by the FBl
你毁坏了他们的数据库．
whose database you crippled last year
在这一行中  你是最强的
that you are the best in the business.
所以我要给你一个选择
So you're about to be given a choice.
如果我说不呢
What if I say no?
对不起
Excuse me, but is this really
但这就是我们的最佳人选吗
the best we could do?
我是说…
I mean...
你能说多少种语言
How many languages do you speak?
5种
Five, actually.
是吗  我只会一种
Well, I speak one.
一  零  一  零  零
One, zero, one, zero, zero.
就靠这个  我可以窃取你的金钱  你的秘密
With that, I could steal your money, your secrets
你的性取向  甚至你的一生
your sexual fantasies, your whole life
只要我想  不论何时何地都能做到
any country, any place, anytime I want.
我们的力量是你所无法想象的
We multitask like you breathe.
即使我努力  也无法做到象你那么迟钝的思考
I couldn't think as slow as you if I tried.
你有什么值得…
Do you have any idea...?
好了  好了
Okay, hey. Hey!
让他松口气
Let's just, let's give the kid a break.
好的  这是电话
Okay, it's a phone.
只是个电话
It's just a phone.
老鼠  我们有大麻烦了
Rat, we got a big problem.
很多人将会死去
A lot of people are going to die.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
哪种帮助
What kind of help?
信息操控
Information control.
我们需要你来控制因特网上的信息流动
We need you to control the flow of information on the lnternet.
你在做梦吧  没有人能控制因特网
You're dreaming. Nobody controls the Net.
你可以吗  在有无限制的资源供应的条件下
Could you... with unlimited resources?
你是要让我黑掉整个星球
You want me to hack the planet?
他想让我黑掉整个星球
He wants me to hack the planet.
用这个电话  你可以永远免费拨打
You've got free long distance
长途电话了
on that phone... forever.
好吧
Okay.
我决定了
If I decide to do this...
我需要大量的
I'm going to need an unlimited supply
Xena驱动器和热水袋
of Xena tapes and Hot Pockets.
热水袋
Hot Pockets?
是的  这可以帮我集中精神
They help me concentrate.
听起来不错
Sounds fair.
切尔斯少校  他们在等你
Major Childs, they're ready for you.
切尔斯少校
Major Childs
据证实
a clarification
你单独提出的
You and you alone were responsible
航天飞机的降落路线
for proposing the descent vectors
都是可靠的  对吗
for the shuttle, correct?
是的  将军
Yes, General.
我们认定这次艾德华号
We have determined that the Class "A" landing mishap
A级着陆事故的起因是缘自于
experienced by the Shuttle Endeavour
受地磁场干扰而造成的
was caused by biased navigational data
错误的航线数据
from the ground due to a brief geomagnetic disturbance.
切尔斯少校  在决定降落路线
Major Childs, the resourcefulness you showed
方面你显示了你的足智多谋
in determining the descent vectors proved
和异常高超的航空技巧
that you have exceptional navigation skills.
你在太空计划和美国空军里
You've brought much credit upon yourself
为自己赢得了荣誉
the space program and the United States Air Force.
恭喜你  少校
Congratulations, Major.
你被重新指派给
You are reassigned
艾弗森指挥官和飞行主管斯蒂克利
with Commander lverson and Flight Director Stickley
马上去进行一项新的任务
to a new mission effective immediately.
车正等在外面
Transportation is waiting outside.
祝你好运  少校
Good luck and Godspeed, Major.
你确定要用这条领带
Are you sure you want to wear this tie?
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是说你看上去好紧张
I mean, you look so nervous about it.
你看上去真…
You look so...
你怎么样啊
So, how are you holding up?
哦  我很好  我很好
Oh, hi. I'm good, I'm good.
我将要对几百人宣告
I'm about to tell a couple hundred people
世界的末日就要到了
the world is going to end.
好的…
Well...
至少我有过好日子
I've had better days.
你看起来还不错
You look good.
不  他看上去并不好
No, you don't look good.
他怎么把领带系成那样
Why did he touch his tie like that?
托马斯让我和你谈谈
Thomas, let me speak with you for a moment.
听着  你真的不让我来做吗
Listen, wouldn't you rather I did this?
我是说把这份荣耀…
I mean, given my reputation, I think that...
不  不凯斯是这里的领导人
No. No, Keyes is in the lead here, Zimsky.
是的托马斯．但这是科学史上
Yes. Thomas, this is the most important
最重要的一次行动
scientific operation in history.
以我的身份来说  我认为做这个演讲应该是我的工作
And given my status, I feel that it's my job to present...
＂命运计划＂才是你的工作  辛斯基
Project Destiny was your job, Zimsky.
你已经越权了
And you went way beyond authorized limits.
让我告诉你…  还是让我告诉你吧
And let me tell... And let me tell you
我真想知道  是不是＂命运＂造成了这场灾难
I still, I want to know if Destiny caused this problem.
绝对不可能  但它也许是一种解决方法
It's highly unlikely, but it may be the solution.
现在  我还要完成检查
Now, I have not finished checking...
对不起
Excuse me.
我很高兴我原来的说法是错的
Rebecca... I'm so glad I was wrong.
向右越过左边那…
Right over left...
不不  另外那个左边的  另外那个
No, the other left, the other left.
先生们．
Gentlemen.
先生们
艾弗森指挥官  切尔斯少校
Commander lverson, Major Childs,
这些是你的全体成员
this is your crew
布雷兹博士  他了解这船
Dr. Brazzleton knows the ship
辛斯基博士  精通行星学
Dr. Zimsky knows the planet
莱维柯博士  精通武器系统
Dr. Leveque knows the weapons system
对不起  女士优先
Excuse me, ladies first.
然后是  凯斯博士…
And Dr. Keyes...
凯斯博士是导航系统的发明者  所以…
Dr. Keyes built the navigation system, so...
你好．我是蕾贝卡·切尔斯
Hi. Rebecca Childs.
鲍勃·艾弗森
Bob lverson.
他们就是你的伙伴…做什么的…
These are your fellow... fellow... what?
地心旅行
Terranauts?
你好
Hello.
所有人都到了
All this brain power over here
他们都在等着
is starting to smell like burning batteries.
你们最好赶快来
Y'all better come and join in.
好的
Yeah.
这是件很简单的事请  对我来说是最难的
It's the simplest things that are the hardest, huh?
对  这太正式了
Yeah. It's official.
我是这次会议上资格最年轻的一个
I'm the least-qualified person on this base.
凯斯博士  我确定人们都在指望着你
Dr. Keyes, I'm sure the people in charge
他们都对你充满信心
have every confidence in you.
问题就在于被指望着
Well, the problem is that I'm in charge.
是的  我知道了
Yeah, I know.
我能帮你吗
Can I help you?
是的  劳驾
Yes, please.
你是个宇航员并且你也会系领带
You're an astronaut, and you can tie a Windsor?
有没有你做不到的事情
Is there anything you can't do?
就我所知  没有
Not that I'm aware of.
这真是令人不敢相信
I find that incredibly intimidating.
是的  大部分人都是这样
Yep. Most people do.
这里
Here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
让我来介绍  我们项目的负责人约书亚·凯斯博士
Let me introduce our project leader, Dr. Joshua Keyes.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
晚上好
Good evening. Good evening.
这看上去像一次匿名的诺贝尔颁奖会议
This looks like a meeting for Nobel Prize Winners Anonymous.
我知道你们都是自己领域内的佼佼者
I know you are all the finest in your fields
并且是经过很长的旅途来到这里
and have come a long way to be here.
所以  我会给出我们未来3个月的大纲
So, I'll outline our program over the next three months.
布雷兹博士会监督船的制造
Dr. Brazzleton will supervise the building of a ship
用来探索我们这颗行星的核心的船
which is capable of reaching the center of our planet.
到达那里之后  它将引发一场
Once there, it will deliver an explosive charge
足够巨大的爆炸  来使地核重新运动
Iarge enough to restart its core.
辛斯基博士会计算
Dr. Zimsky will calculate
需要的爆炸当量
the scale of the explosion needed.
我的项目是模拟
This is a program I designed to simulate the effect
在地核进行核爆炸后的结果
of nuclear detonations on the core.
如果我的计算没有错的话  任何方向上的
If my calculations are correct, a tiny nudge in any direction
轻微推动都会使地核恢复正常运转
will force the core back into its normal flow.
对行星来说“轻微推动”是什么意义
What's a "tiny nudge" in planetary terms?
一千兆吨当量是高还是低
A thousand megatons, give or take?
最多就是这么高了  因为更大的力量
T ops. Because any more than that
都会使地核变得不稳定
would create a core instability.
我们已经制造了一些200兆吨的弹头
We made a few monster warheads in the 200-megaton range.
布雷兹  你认为  这艘船能成功输送这5个人吗
Braz, do you think the ship can handle five of these babies?
是的  我可以加大输出的功率
Yeah. I can enlarge the ejection pod...
请原谅  虽然我不是这方面的专家
Forgive me, but, you know, I know I'm not the expert here
但如果地核过厚或者过薄又怎么样
but what if the core is thicker or thinner?
我的意思是  如果它不像你所认为的那样又该怎么办
I mean, what if it's not what you think it is?
这会影响我们爆炸的方式吗
Isn't that going to affect the way the explosions are...?
是啊是啊
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
如果地核是乳酪做的又该怎么办
And what if the core is made of cheese?
这些全是猜想  指挥官
This is all best guess, Commander.
所有的科学都是最好的猜想
That's all science is, is best guess.
所以我的猜想就是  你不知道
So my best guess is you don't know.
真是好运  这对那些爱好和平  的人来说是个讽刺
With luck, irony will break for the good guys for once,
世界上最具毁灭性的武器
and the world's biggest weapons of mass destruction
会帮助我们拯救世界
will help save the world.
这艘船会以一个小的
The ship will be powered
试验用反应堆作动力
by a small experimental nuclear reactor.
它会被分散在6个车间里
It will be divided into six compartments
就好像汽车在装配线上
Iike cars on a train
机动部分在航行车间
the locomotive unit, navigation department
还有生活部分  工程部  爆破部
Iiving quarters, engineering, bomb compartment
最后的是武器控制部分
and finally the weapons-control module.
在斜45度角的情况下  各部分会以
Up to a 45 degree angle, every compartment will be held level
螺栓型的平衡环连在一条直线上
by these gyro control gimbals.
如果有一部分坏了
But if we do breach a section
隔离门会自动锁紧
bulkhead doors engage automatically
封锁红色的部分  并将之排除
seal off the section in red, and eject.
排除是最好的选择吗
Is ejection really the best option?
是唯一的选择
Only option.
任何损坏的部分都会降低整体的性能
Each damaged compartment degrades the entire hull.
目标非常简单
The objective is simple.
阻碍也很大
The obstacles are gigantic.
我们需要来自世界各地得帮助
We're going to need all the help in the world,
但为了避免惊慌和混乱
but if we are to avoid panic and chaos,
我们不能让外界  知道这里发生了什么事情
the world at large can never know what's happening here.
那也正是我们的＂老鼠＂先生的世界
Which is where our friend Mr. Rat comes in.
这叫做病毒机器人
It's called Virus-bot.
这是一种能够查找文件的机器人
It's a computer virus that will seek out files
可以查找任何网页上我们所指定的关键字
anywhere on the Web that contain keywords that we designate
并把它们消去
and wipes them out.
这就是我的功夫  真的很强啊
This is my Kung-Fu, and it is strong.
在我们面前有无数的难题
Meanwhile, there are a million puzzles ahead of us
我们只有3个月来解决他们
and we have three months to solve them.
我们有一支忠诚机智的队伍
We have a committed and ingenious team.
我们拥有充足的资源
We have every resource available to us
我们有世界上最好的
and we have the best
科学与技术支持
of the world's scientific and technical talents on our side.
在你们的帮助下  我们可以  我们必须  成功
With your help we can, we must... succeed.
共鸣管的回馈．
Feedback in the resonance tube.
向我汇报  先生们
T alk to me, gentlemen.
我们迷路了
We are losing
整体上来说
structural integrity.
不行  没有回馈
No, it's not feedback.
我相信  这是推进器的故障
It's an impeller malfunction, I believe.
不  绝对不会是推进器  如果真是这样…
No, it's not, no. If it were an impeller malfunction...
看在上帝的份上  布雷兹zleton  快打电话
For God's sakes, Braz, make the call!
不  我来打  应该是我
No, I'll make the call. I should make the call.
速度65节
65 knots.
深度  805 000英尺
Depth, 8-5 thousand feet.
伙计们…
Look, guys...
这真是场灾难
It's a disaster!
任务失败
你们不懂＂向我汇报＂是什么意思吗  伙计们
What part of "talk to me" don't you guys understand?
第22次小组模拟
For the 22nd time in a row,
地球上所有人都死了
everyone on Earth is dead.
安静的休息一会
Let's take a little quiet time
然后你们要再试一次
and you all are going to try this again.
这是什么
What is this?
这个…这是我发明的
It's... I invented it.
你就靠这个在地下驾驶
It's how you're going to... going to steer underground.
这个…
It's, um...
接收不太好
not very good reception.
是的  你看见了
Well, you're looking
穿过50码外3英尺厚的障碍
through three feet of lead at 50 yards away, so...
算不错的了
it ain't bad.
看起来像医院的X线扫描系统
It's like a CAT scan at a hospital
但是这个是不一样的
but it's-it's souped-up.
我是为了做地底
I invented it
测量才发明它的
for Deep Earth surveying.
政府参与进来买下了我的研究
And then the government came in, bought my research
付清了我的  助学贷款  并且聘请我做顾问
paid off my student loan guys and made me a consultant.
对不起  这仪器非常精密
I'm sorry, this is really delicate.
它只按我的意愿来工作
and I have it just the way I want it.
让我来做
So... excuse me.
好的
yeah.
在他们的负责人辞职之后  他们就把我拉进来了
Then they brought me in when the pacemakers quit
看起来我就好像个“超级男孩”
and... boom you know, I'm Apocalypse Boy.
“超级男孩”
Apocalypse Boy?
是的  我有这个主题系列的T恤衫
Yeah. I'm having T -shirts made up.
那种帽子应该卖得更好吧
Well, hats sell better.
你看  这真的很有意思  因为…
You know, it's funny, because that is...
那个是不能移动的
right where it should be.
好的
Well...
真是令人惭愧  影像的边缘还很粗糙
I'm sorry. I'm a little ragged around the edges.
我正在试图令它的对焦更精确
I'm just trying to get this thing to focus correctly.
这真是个很酷的想法  我想我可以…
This is really cool, but can I just...?
看上去好多了  确实好多了
It's better. It's better.
天啊  我讨厌这样的天空
God, I hate this sky.
一次撞毁还不能阻止你吗
Crashing one ship isn't enough for you?
好的练习会令事情事半功倍
Practice makes perfect.
你可以练习所有的项目
You can practice all you like.
但这并不表示你可以担负起指挥官的责任
It doesn't mean you're ready to sit in that seat.
您是在提醒我吗  长官
So you keep reminding me, sir.
我知道  也许你听不进去这些话
You know, I doubt you're even going to listen to this
但我仍然要说
but I'm going to give it a shot.
做一个领导并不是看你有多高的技术
Being a leader isn't about ability.
它所要求的是责任感
It's about responsibility.
我知道了  长官
Got it, sir.
不  你没有明白
No, you don't, Beck.
我是说  你还并不具备令人信赖的
I mean, you're not just responsible
做出决定的能力
for making good decisions.
你必须对一切不利的情况负起责任
You have to be responsible for the bad ones.
你必须时刻准备好面对最坏的情况
You got to be ready to make the shitty call.
你为什么认为我不行
What makes you think I'm not?
因为你太优秀了
Because you're so good.
你从来没被你所不能做到的事打败过
You haven't hit anything you couldn't beat.
我是说
I mean, hell,
你确是一个人演算  出了拯救航天飞机的轨道
you were the one who figured out how to save the shuttle.
这使得我和  航空航天局的人看起来像是废物
You made me, you made the rest of NASA just look like an ass.
你是天生的赢家
It's just that you're used to winning...
但没有经历过失败的人是当不了领导的
...and you're not really a leader until you've lost.
这项计划已经花费了200亿美元
$20 billion has been spent developing this system...
伙计们  航空航天局里的厨子都…
Oh, come on, guys, the chefs at NASA...
我想喝酒  我需要酒
I want wine! I need wine!
那不符合营养学  在五天里…
It's about nutrition. In five days, I think...
那是高空的静电释放
That's high-level static discharge.
我想我们应该检查一下
I think we should check this out.
看上去情况不妙了
This doesn't look so good.
这种巨大的闪电风暴
It's a lightning superstorm.
将在世界各地爆发
Popping up all over the world.
继续跟踪它的动向
Got them. Tracking.
罗马要遭殃了
Rome does not look good.
地球崩溃的速度比我们预料得更快
This planet is decaying faster than we thought.
这还只是个开始
It's just the start.
不久之后电磁场就会裂开
Soon they'll be EM spikes
致命的微波会从缝隙间辐射进来…
and microwaves will break through the weak spots and...
好吧  该让这艘船出发了
All right. Get this ship in the ground. Now.
南太平洋  马丽亚娜海沟
真是个平静的夏日啊
Summer in the Pacific.
对啊  世界已经天翻地覆了
Yeah, the world is inside out.
过一会我会挽救这一切的…
I was saving this for later, but...
现在要先…
this is the time for...
约书亚  你不会介意吧
Josh, do you mind?
不  绝对不会
No, not at all.
我们应该给我们这个孩子取个名字
We should have a name for this baby.
它其实叫做维吉尔
she's called Virgil, actually.
维吉尔就是带着我们走入地域的诗人的名字
Virgil-- the poet that led our man into the depths of hell?
很好  我认为这个名字很合适
That's it. That's appropriate, I guess.
好吧  敬我们的维吉尔
Well, here's to Virgil.
敬我们的地球
To the planet.
-干杯  -干杯
-To Virgil. -To Virgil.
没有闪光灯  没有记者  没有人来欢送
No flashbulbs, no press, nobody cheering.
真是奇怪啊
It's.... weird.
我们走吧
Let's go.
船舱电压  TS1 3.5
Cabin pressure, TSl, 3.5.
完毕
Check.
发动机控制系统开启
ECS cabin repress open.
VLV封闭
And repress VLV closed.
完毕
Check.
固定安全阀
Fluid dump valve.
我们就要开始我们的旅程了
We are about to begin our journey
让我们进入宇宙的中心
into the heart of the cosmos
到达地球的核心
into the very core of our own planet.
-在那里我们会找到…  -完毕
-Where we find therein... -Check.
宇宙万物的奥秘
the secrets of the universe...
…3.5  PSl
.. :3.5 PSl.
…时间的秘密…
...the mysteries of time...
无线电频率锁定
LM circuit lockup.
-完毕  -…还有… 未来的希望
-Check. -...hope for the future.
发出信号
And signal.
控制中心  这是维吉尔
Deep Earth Control, this is Virgil.
信号检测完毕
Signal check.
这里是控制中心
This is Deep Earth Control.
我已经准备好这次的赌博了
I have thumbs-up across the board.
你可以启动了
You are clear to initiate power-up.
反应堆输出正常
Reactor power confirmed.
每分钟1 000转  我们可以倒数计时了  各就各位
At 1, 000 rpm, we will countdown to launch. On your mark.
指挥塔准备开始倒数计时
Pad leader, stand by for launch.
好的  维吉尔
All right, Virgil.
系统
就位
Mark.
开始倒数  10 9
Gantry count. Ten, nine,
8, 7, 6, 5, 4
eight, seven, six, five, four,
3, 2, 1...
three, two, one...
下潜
Launch.
500英尺
500 feet.
准备启动激光系统
Leveling out.
好了伙计们  我们笔直前进吧
Okay, guys, let's swing forward.
800英尺
800 feet.
点火  小贝
Light them up, Beck.
启动导航系统
Gyro leveling operational.
启动外壳损伤检查系统
Hull integrity holding.
我来把船体调整为15度倾角
I'm going to keep her nose down about 15 degrees and...
我的天哪
Oh, my goodness.
它们在向我们发信号
They're singing to us.
这是因为维吉尔号的共振引起的
Virgil's resonance tubes are powered up,
所以它们作出回应
so they're vibrating sub sonically.
实际上  是我们在向它们发信号
Actually, we're singing to them.
深度
What's our depth?
1600英尺  裂缝两边都有足够的空间
1, 600 feet, plenty of room on both sides.
船体完好无损
Hull integrity is good.
确定
You sure?
增加推进器的速度
Let's increase impeller speed.
我想我们需要附加控制了
I think we'll be needing additional control.
史狄克  有地震信号
Stick, I'm getting a seismic reading.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
T级  水下地震
T -phase. Underwater earthquake.
你仍然认为水下发射是个好主意吗
Still think the water-launch was a good idea?
是的  是的  我选择这里是因为这里的地壳很薄
Yes, yes, I chose this location because the crust is thin here.
地震行为越来越频繁了
The downside is... there's lots of seismic activity.
4000英尺
4, 000 feet.
看到那块石头了吗
You see that rock?
好像不大妙
That is not good.
我们无法控制方向了
We're losing steering here.
有一股暗流在侧面推我们
There's some kind of crosscurrent.
14000英尺
14, 000 feet.
伙计们  系好安全带
Okay, guys, fasten your seat belts.
我们要刹车了
We're turning into the skid.
18000英尺
18, 000.
18500英尺
18, 500.
他们的速度太快了
They're going way too fast.
21000英尺
21, 000 feet.
我们就要到达地壳了
We hit the wall,
我们就像是高速公路上的兔子
we're rabbits on the highway.
压力  压力  压力  压力
Pressure, pressure, pressure, pressure.
你是什么意思  压力
What do you mean, pressure?
你好像说过这是不可能的
I thought you said this thing was indestructible!
压力只会让我们更强大
I said the pressure makes us stronger.
压力还不够
We just don't have enough of it yet.
已经25000英尺了  准备启动吧
We're at 25, 000 feet. Pull out, sir.
不行
Can't.
-什么  -我们周围的空间还不够
-What? -We're locked in.
等到全速
Go to full throttle.
准备启动主激光器和辅助激光器
Standby to engage front and lateral lasers, please.
还有10秒种我们就要撞上地壳了
But what if we hit bottom in ten seconds here?
再等几秒钟
Just give it a couple more seconds.
就发射激光
The lasers will fire.
不行  时间不够了
No, there's not enough time for power-up.
27000英尺
27, 000 feet.
准备发射激光
The lasers will deploy.
29000英尺
29, 000 feet.
快点  发射
Do it!
-发射  -现在
-Do it! -Now.
收到信号了
And we've got a signal.
太棒了
All right.
很好
切换为电力钻探系统
Switching on electron spin burst transmitters.
每五分钟检测一次
Plotting through lowest density material
周围环境的密度
reconfiguring every five minutes.
船体完好无损  反应堆工作正常
Hull integrity 100%. Reactor power 100%.
武器仓完好无损
All green on the bomb compartment.
航速60节
Speed is 60 knots.
外面真热
Hot damn.
我们将在十五分钟内穿过地壳
All right, we'll be through the crust in 15 minutes
然后进入内部
and into the mantle.
如果我们能挺住  24小时内到达地核
24 hours to the core, and then assuming we survive...
-假如  -没错  假如
-Assuming? -Yes, assuming.
然后还需要15小时到达里核
Another 15 hours to the inner core-outer core border.
干得好
They're doing well.
地壳只不过是一层石头
The crust is just rock.
现在才开始真正的挑战
Now it gets interesting.
维吉尔号  检查一下周围的情况
Virgil, can we get a status check?
我们要进入地球内部了
We're about to make the transition into the mantle.
加油
Come on, come on.
外面的压力居然这么大
Well, exterior pressure is 800, 000 pounds
每平方英寸800000磅
per square inch.
船体完好度100%
And hull integrity is 100%.
好像我们在这个星球的记忆里面
It is as if we we're diving through the memories
潜水
of the planet.
我们好像要穿过记忆
But we are about to pass from memory
到达深层的疯狂地带
into madness.
你要一路这么念下去你那
Are you going to be doing that Carl Sagan narration
蹩脚的诗吗
all the way to the core?
-请再说一遍  -我说
-I beg your pardon? -I said...
我对我的学生  我的读者有这个义务
I-I have an obligation to my students, to my readers...
你有这个义务吗
An obligation to make a book deal perhaps?
两本书  如果你想知道真像
Two book deals, if you'd like to know the truth.
我以前读过最后一本书  写得不是很好
I read that last book. It wasn't very good.
真的吗  真的
Oh, really? Really?
你什么时候学习读书写字的
When did you learn how to read?
12小时  深度700英里
嘿
People
辛斯基博士和凯斯博士过来一下
Drs. Zimsky and Keyes?
你们是我们的地球物理学家
You guys are our resident geophysicists.
看看这是什么东西
What do you make of this?
这是一团大杂烩  由很多东西组成的
The mantle is a chemical hodgepodge of... a variety of elements...
说 “我不知道”
Say it with me "l don't know."
那么  船长
Well, Commander
聪明人说  当你不确定的时候  应该四处走走确定一下
wise men say, "When in doubt, you should go around."
不行  这东西太大了
No. It's too big.
我们的转向不够快
We turn too slow.
如果有我们不能穿过的东西
Anything that we can't go through
它应该是黑色的
displays as black.
那么  这到底是什么
So what's... what's static?
什么也不是
It's nothing.
什么意思
What do you mean?
什么也不是
It's nothing.
这里应该是空的
It's empty space.
我
I...
我忘记教电脑识别这种虚空状态了
I never taught the computer how to read empty space.
我也忘记教维吉尔号学习飞行了
And I never taught Virgil how to fly.
天哪
God!
上帝啊
dear God.
赛吉  你还好吗
Serge, you all right?
我没事
Yeah.
有人受伤吗
Anybody hurt?
我没事  你呢
No. You okay?
我也没事
Yeah.
那是什么  那是什么
What's that? What is that?
从冷却系统来的  快关掉
From the cooling system. Shut that down.
关掉
Shut it down.
我告诉过你要绕开她走
I told you to go around her.
没人听我的
Nobody listens to me.
我们到底在哪里
Where in God's name are we?
我们的激光钻头坏了
Whatever has us jammed up is inside our lasers.
关掉它们吧
Shut them down.
我们哪也去不了了
We're not going anywhere.
能源关闭
Powering down.
约书亚  想想有什么办法把我们弄出来吗
Josh, is there any other image you can pull up?
没有
Nope.
无论这是什么  它已经把我们卡住了
Whatever it is, it's also inside our MRl cameras.
我们得出去一下
We have to go outside.
什么
What?
相信我吧  虽然我也不愿意出去
Believe me, I hate to admit it
我想他是对的
but I think he's right.
我去  我想采集一些样品
I'm coming. I want to collect samples.
等等  等等
Wait, hang on, hang on.
等一下  首先问题是
Wait, wait, the first problem is
这艘船的出口只有一个
the only way out of the ship... is the way we came in,
就是在推进器那里
which is through the impeller outlet...
现在温度足足有5000度
Which is still at 5, 000 degrees.
我的意思是
Exactly, I mean...
首先要用液化氮把它冷却一下
I'll just flush it with liquid nitrogen
开启冷却系统
from the cooling system.
等一下
Wait. The cooling system
冷却系统就是做这个用的吗
that's keeping us from roasting to death in this ship?
没错  是这艘船的一部分
Well, just a small part of it.
决定一下吧
Alternatives?
所有人
Anybody.
哇  这景象
Whoa, whoa, that's it.
好像全都是水晶  巨大的水晶石
It's like a giant... giant crystal.
我们到底在哪里
Where the hell are we?
好消息是
Well, the good news is,
看起来我们的工作服能够适应这里的压力
it looks like the suits can take the pressure.
就是这东西把我们的激光钻头给卡住了
It's completely jammed the laser assembly.
我希望
We just... we got to hope,
我们能把这东西弄出来后
if we can cut it loose,
-激光钻头还能工作  -小心点
-they're still functional. -Careful!
好的
Okay.
拿到了
Got it.
小贝  把灯打开
Beck, try the lights, will you?
开灯
Lighting up.
-好壮观  -我的天哪
-Oh, it's magnificent. -Oh, my God.
阿拉丁藏宝的山洞
Aladdin's cave.
简直是水晶大峡谷
It's like a crystal Grand Canyon.
我想这些都是
I think it's a geode.
不过我不太明白
But I don't understand
这些东西怎么会在这里
how it could have survived down here.
可能这里是钴层
Cobalt shell, maybe?
我想
No. I-I mean,
在这种5000度高温的环境下
in a magma environment of 5, 000 degrees.
一定有什么东西在保护这些水晶层
Something would have to protect it.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
辛斯基
Zimsky.
怎么了
Yeah?
我们在一个宝石大厅里面
We're inside a giant gem bubble
四周是钴做的茧
wrapped in a cobalt cocoon
地表以下700英里
700 miles below the surface of the Earth.
糟糕的一天
Hell of a day.
一点没错
Yes, it is.
开始切割吧
I'll start cutting.
好的  布雷兹
Okay, Braz.
我去检查一下船体
I'm going to check the hull.
如果需要帮忙就喊我一声
Call me if you need me.
好的
Okay.
天哪
Oh, no.
-辛斯基  -怎么了
-Zimsky! -Yeah?
辛斯基  快看
Zimsky, look!
紫水晶
It's an amethyst.
天哪
Oh, God
刚才我们把外层钴壳弄坏了
we've breached the shell.
伙计们  你们快回去
Guys, you don't have to be here!
你们都上船
I want you back inside!
我想我们确实应该上船
Well, I think that means me.
命令就是命令
Orders are orders.
等等  约书亚
Wait, Josh.
我的氧气管掉了
The problem is I'm losing oxygen.
布雷兹  我该怎么办
Braz, what can I do?
快检查一下后面的氧气箱
Check the feeds for me.
快点检查一下
Check the feeds for me, Josh.
快点
Quick!
我正在努力
I'm coming. I'm coming as fast as I can.
快点  再这么下去
Hey, guys, at this rate
三分钟后我们就要被岩浆淹没了
we have three minutes before the lava gets to us.
快点
Come on, guys.
加油
Come on.
没有氧气工作不了
It's not going to work without oxygen!
需要氧气
We're losing oxygen!
修好了  快点切
I fixed it. Now cut!
非常好  正常工作了
That's good. It's working now.
正常工作了
It's working well now!
非常好  约书亚！
That's good, Josh!
约书亚的生理信号不太稳定
Josh's vital signs are dropping.
什么
What?
赛吉！
Serge!
就差一点了  约书亚
You're almost there, Josh.
约书亚
Josh!
Joshua!
好吧  伙计们
Okay, guys,
接通氧气管
connect the oxygen.
怎么样  行了吗
Braz, you got that?
好了
Yes. Connected!
很好  我去检查一下那些激光器
Good. I got to check these lasers.
好的  小贝  把它们暂时先关掉
Okay, Beck, turn them over.
只留下前面的如果你不介意的话
Pre-lasers only, if you don't mind.
明白
Initiating.
干得不错
This better work.
要涨潮了
The tide's really coming in.
恩
Yes!
我们真幸运
We got lucky I think we're going
我想我们就要去游泳了
to swim right out of this one.
鲍勃
Bob?
怎么了
Huh?
鲍勃
Bob?
Bob...
布雷兹快过来
Braz, come on, it's over.
来了来了
Okay. Okay.
小贝  小贝
Beck! Beck!
我们就来
We're coming in.
快准备开船
Initiate start sequence.
小贝
Beck
-小贝听到了吗 - 小心
-Beck, do you hear me? -Careful.
打开推进器
Start the impellers!
快开门
The door, open the door.
启动隔离门
Activate bulkhead doors!
快点  小贝
Now, Beck!
怎么样  你太虚弱了
You okay? You're going to be weak.
还好
You're okay.
那么
So, um...
我们有些好消息  并且
we have some good news, and, uh...
还有些坏消息
and we have some bad news.
我要听好消息
Good news. I'll take good news.
好消息是我们还活着  还能动
Well, we're alive and we're moving.
这就是好消息
That's g... that's good news.
这里可真热
Oh, it is hot in here.
没错  硝化甘油漏出去了
Yeah, that nitro we flushed out
我们的制冷系统出了问题
of the cooling system, it-it's causing things
只是有点热而已
just to heat up a little.
我要回去了
I'm going to go back
调整一下
and just make some adjustments.
让我来帮你一下
I'll lend you a hand.
我来检查一下你的心跳
I'm going to check your heartbeat, okay?
谢谢布雷兹
Thanks, Braz. Appreciate it.
恩  坏消息是什么
So, that's the bad news?
也不是真的很坏
That's not too bad.
不  艾弗森  指挥官死了
No. Commander lverson died.
但是
But...
我们活下来
we're living, and he would want to...
就是为了完成他的遗志
he'd want us to complete our mission
所以我想我们都要
so I think that it's important that we all...
明白了
It's all right.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很难过
I'm sorry.
我们为他默哀吧
Let's give him a second, okay?
我们有这个义务
He deserves that.
天哪  这些东西真大
Oh, God, this all just seems too big, doesn't it?
也许我们做得事情是不可实现的
I think you were attempting the impossible.
试图拯救拯救这个世界  但是
You were trying to save the world, and...
我们已经没有退路了
it's overwhelming.
我来这里是为了救我的妻子和两个孩子
I came here to save my wife and my two children
还有整整60亿人  太多了
and... six billion lives it's too much.
我只希望  我能够
I just hope I'm-I'm smart enough
对她们三个尽到我的责任
and brave enough to save three.
干得好  约书亚  非常好
You did a nice job, Joshua. Very nice. Great.
你也不错
You'd have done the same thing.
呵呵  也许吧
Well, maybe, maybe.
嘿  谁在开船
Hey... who's steering the ship?
现在是自动导航
Video screen autopilot.
我希望它能分清路
I hope he knows the way.
希望如此
You and me both.
你真的是个大学教授
So... you're really a college professor?
你不是CIA
You're not from the ClA
或者NSA或者随便其他什么组织的人
or the NSA or any of those three-letter places?
没错  我就是一个大学教授
No. I am a boring college professor.
真不是地方
Wrong place, wrong place.
这是我见过最勇敢的事情了
That was the bravest thing I've ever seen.
我只是
Well, I just, I just...
你知道吗  刚才没有氧气的时候
Listen, the lack of oxygen
我简直像个小女孩一样软弱无力
kept me from weeping like a little girl
在危险面前我总是很软弱
as is my custom in dangerous situations.
任务第二天
伙计们  我们已经到了地核表面了
Hey, guys, we're close to the mantle core interface.
你在哪里
Where are you?
启动操作已经确认
Key's in, Dr. Brazzleton.
准备
Ready.
我们在
We are in the...
号码是  0—1—3－1－9－9－5
Okay, the code... 0-1-3-1-9-9-5.
完美的武器控制
...Iuxurious, beautiful weapons control...
检查核能控制系统
checking the controls on the nukes.
今天是我女儿的生日
This is the birthday of my daughter.
0-1-3-1-9-9-5
0-1-3-1-9-9-5.
-准备好了吗 -好了
-Ready? -Yeah.
3  2  1
Three, two and one..
谢谢
Thank you.
一切正常
Green. All green.
很好  让我们保持同步
Great. So we have to synchronize
现在是分支系统
the babies now.
马上
Just a second.
很好
There.
很好  把它们放好
All right, now let's put them to bed.
辛斯基  能来一下吗
Zimsky, could you please come up here for a second?
来了
Yes?
照理说我们是不能通过黑色区域的
We're not supposed to go through anything black.
那么就不要在那里走好了
Yes, so please don't.
这是什么？
What is this?
到处都是
They're scattered everywhere.
天哪  这是钻石
Oh, my God! They're diamonds!
太棒了！
Great.
你最好坐好 系上安全带
You might want to sit down and buckle up.
很可能会有碰撞发生
We're on a collision course here.
好的  小心点
All rightie. Careful.
伙计们  我们在躲避这些像暗礁一样的钻石
Guys, we're dodging diamonds the size of Cape Cod
小心点
so bear with me.
还是不够敏捷
Not exactly nimble here.
钻石  我也想要
Diamonds? I want some.
我能帮什么忙吗
Can I help?
噢
Ooh!
没关系  没关系
Okay. It's okay.
恩  看起来好像搞定了
Okay, it looks like we're in the clear.
机舱受损
Breach!
快从武器控制室出来！
Guys! Weapons control, get out!
快出来
Get out now!
赛吉
Serge!
赛吉  你在干什么
Serge! What the hell are you doing?
快点
Come on!
我的笔记本
My notebook!
快点
Now!
赛吉
Serge!
带上　　　约书亚
T ake the time reg, Joshua!
赛吉  快点
Come on Serge! Come on!
我的笔记本  不能丢掉
My notes! You'll need them!
不
No!
看在上帝的份上  快走
God, no, Serge!
没事的
It's okay.
赛吉  不  不要去
Serge, come on! No!
赛吉
Serge!
快点
Come on, man!
-扔掉那破盒子 -我们需要它
-Leave the box! -We need the box!
我们能救他  我们能把他救出来
We can get him! We can get him out!
坚持住  赛吉
Hold on, Serge!
小贝  小贝
Beck! Beck!
不要启动自动分离系统！
Override the ejection system!
小贝  不！  如果有一段损坏
Beck, no! One damaged compartment
整艘船都会遭殃
threatens the whole ship!
小贝  小贝
Beck! Beck!
不要启动自动分离系统！
Override the ejection system!
赛吉  我们都在这
Serge, we're right here.
我们会永远记着你
We're not going to forget about you, man.
-约书亚能听到吗　　 -赛吉  赛吉
-Josh, can you hear me? -Serge! Serge...
伙计  仔细看着监视器
Hey, buddy, look in your monitor right now.
赛吉  好好看着你的监视器
Serge, look in your monitor.
我在这  赛吉
I'm right here. Serge...
约书亚  我看不到你
Josh, I can't see you.
布雷兹正在试图开门 坚持住
Braz is going to override the doors manually, okay?
我们正在努力  布雷兹  还要多长时间
We're working on it right now. Braz, how long?
我尽快
Going as fast as I can, Fast as I can.
- 刚才吓死我了　 - 我们现在都在这
-Okay, I'm scared. -We're going right now.
不应该是
Shouldn't be two seconds, all right?
约书亚
Josh!
小贝  中止自动分离系统！
Beck, override the ejection systems, okay?
真糟糕  她好像听不到我
Damn. I don't think Beck can hear me.
赛吉  看着我  赛吉
Serge, look at me now. Serge!
我们安全了  赛吉
Serge, we're right here, okay?
我们不会丢下你不管的  伙计
We're not going to forget about you, man.
我会把你救出去的
I'm going to get you out of here.
我正在努力
We're working on it, all right?
别丢下我
Stay with me here. Okay?
实在没办法了
I don't know what to do.
现在能听到我了吗  很好  是我
Can you hear me now? All right, here I am.
我不会让你走的
I'm not going to let you go, man.
我不会让你走的  你知道吗
I'm not going to let you go, all right?
留下来
Stay with me here, okay?
我要去巴黎
I'm going to come to Paris
我们一定能从这里脱身
and we'll go out, all right? After this.
等到这一切都结束了
After this is all said and done, all right?
赛吉
Serge!
赛吉  赛吉
Serge! Serge!
赛吉
Serge!
爸爸
你没听见我说什么吗？
Did you reset the overrides?
不行  我不能这么做
I never pushed them.
是你让他死的
You let him die.
说实话  你真的想知道
Actually, you really want to know?
我已经杀了他两次
I killed him twice.
第一次是我撞上那钻石的时候
First when I hit the diamond,
然后我没有中止自动分离系统
and then when I didn't hit the override.
你以为我会为我所做的一切感到羞愧吗
Do you want me to feel any worse about that than I already do?
不可能
It's not possible.
你这么自鸣得意做什么
Why are you being so smug about that?
你能做这个决定吗
Could you have made the decision?
-能　 -你能吗
-Yes. -Could you?
我能
Yes, I could've.
如果你打开了开关
If you would've hit that switch,
我就能把他弄出来
I could've got him outta there!
听到了没有
I was yelling for you!
看看这个
Take it and look at it!
我离他只有两英寸
I was two inches from him!
两英寸
I was two inches,
我也告诉过你把门开开
and I told you to put the door up
然而你没有
and you didn't!
你知不知道
I was screaming for you!
你为什么这么做
Why didn't you do it?
因为我决定这么做
Because I had to make that decision.
这是上天注定的
Fate or God...
不
No!
你少给我胡扯什么上帝
Damn it! You leave God out of this!
赛吉死了  然而我们仍然要完成我们的任务
Serge died so that we could complete our job.
没错  任务  拯救世界
Oh, that's right, the job of saving the world.
不是整个世界约书亚  而是赛吉的家人
Not the whole world, Josh! Just three of them.
35小时  深度1900英里
维吉尔号  你们已经接近外核了
Virgil, you are approaching core interface.
怎么样  有信心吗
Are you good to go?
约书亚
Josh?
约书亚  能听到我吗
Josh, can you hear me?
约书亚  听到了吗
随时待命  史迪克
Ready as we'll ever be, Stick.
凯斯 博士
Dr. Keyes.
我在这
Right here.
深入地心  我们状态很好  信心十足
Deep Earth, we are green and good to go.
要加速了
We just got a huge speed jump.
现在的速度是95节
We're at 95 knots.
110节
110.
130  140
130... 140.
地核和我们预料的不太一样
Our speed's jumped because the density of the core
所以我们的速度不太正常
is different than our estimates.
地核的密度比我们想象的要小
It's lighter than we thought.
情况比预料的要好
So much for best guesses.
对此我很满意
I'm fine with this.
这样下去  我们  什么
At this rate, we'll, what
五小时内到达里核
hit the inner core in a little over five hours.
好运气终于来了
I think we finally bought some luck.
布雷兹
Braz.
-什么事  -你可以
-Yeah. -Would you please
帮忙重新计算一下地核密度
punch the new core density into the equations
对爆破的影响吗
for the nuclear detonation?
下载假定情况…完成
这应该够了
Please tell me this is enough.
好的
Okay.
你是说我们那1000兆吨级的核弹
You're telling me the 1, 000 megatons of nuclear warheads
还是不能起到作用
we hauled down here isn't going to cut it?
不是  地核的密度比我们预想的要小
No. This core material is too thin.
-什么  -所以爆炸的
-What? -The energy waves from
冲击波传播的一定不会很远
the explosion won't spread far enough.
根本不可能起到什么作用
They'll just bleed away into nothing.
也对
That's it.
我们回去  我们回去
We go home. We go home.
-回去 -什么
-Home? -What?
指挥官死了
Our Commander is dead.
武器专家也死了
Our weapons specialist is dead.
武器控制系统也坏了
Our weapons control systems are gone.
我们甚至都不能确定  核弹是否还能正常工作
We don't know whether we can arm the nuclear devices,
并且我们的修复地心计划  也出了问题  所以
and our plan to fix the core no longer works. So...
我们已经失败了
we have failed.
我们还没有败
We have not failed.
我们已经败了  回去吧
We have failed, and we go home
我们还有别的方法
and we go to the alternative.
什么方法  你在说什么
What alternative? What are you talking about?
将军  我是康拉德·辛斯基博士
General, this is Dr. Conrad Zimsky.
启动“命运”计划
Destiny is a go.
重复
Repeat.
启动“命运”计划
Destiny is a go.
这下糟了
Damn.
我需要知道一切与我任务有关的资讯
I need to know everything to do my job.
你没必要知道
You don't have to know this.
将军  确保这项任务
General, it is my job
的顺利执行是我的工作
to ensure the safety of this mission.
任何对任务有影响的事情我都需要知道
Anything that affects it is my business.
这个“命运”计划到底是什么
Now what the hell is Destiny?
一种装置
It's a device.
深层地震引发系统  D—E—S—T—I—N—Y
Deep Earth Seismic T rigger lnitiative, DEST -INI. Destiny.
我想现在我们
We had reason to believe
的首要任务是让我们的炸弹
that our enemies were building a weapon
能够产生足够强的力量
that could generate targeted seismic events.
强到能够使这里整个区域发生
They would be able to create massive earthquakes
超大规模的地震
under our territory.
谁能做到
No way of telling who did it.
所以
So?
所以  我们自己来
So... we built one, too.
M．A．D．
M.A.D.
互动破坏系统
Mutually Assured Destruction.
很好  名字不错
A perfect acronym if ever there was one.
很美
Beautiful.
他们做出了原型
They built it first.
我将它改进的更完美
I built it better.
我们可以用
I beamed high-powered
高压电能产生定向的冲击波
electromagnetic energy waves down Deep Earth fault lines, and, you know.
辛斯基你怎么能这么想
Zimsky, what makes you think
你觉得“命运”的威力真的能深入地核吗
that Destiny would even touch the core?
确实有这个威力
'Cause it already did.
这不是意外
This isn't a fluke.
这场灾难就是“命运”造成的
We killed the planet.
你一直在说地核太大了
You keep saying that the core is too big
很容易对核爆作出反应
to be affected by anything short of nukes.
-那么  -地核就象是一部引擎
-So... -The core is an engine.
就算把一个小扳手扔进引擎里
Throw a small wrench into a big engine,
你也能把它弄停
you can still stall it.
总部  维吉尔号呼叫
Deep Earth, this is Virgil.
我们需要完整的“命运”计划细节
We require clarification on the status of Project Destiny.
为什么我们对此一无所知
Why weren't we notified of this, sir?
因为你们根本不需要
Because you didn't need to know, Major.
我知道你对此不满
Now you may not like this.
我也一样不喜欢
I may not like it either.
这是我的工作  我这么做是为了国家
But it's my job, and I do it for my country,
并且如果我们不开发这些武器  别人就可能会开发
and if we don't develop these devices, someone worse will
并且用来对付我们
and they will use them against us.
但是你已经知道情况了
but you have my word.
任何人都没有权力知道这些  谁都不行
No one in this administration no one,
无论如何都不行
had any idea that this could happen.
那么这个“命运”就是你的备用计划了
So the device that killed the planet is your backup plan?
触电能够让心脏停止跳动
An electric shock can stop a heart.
当然也能让心脏启跳
It can certainly restart one.
“命运”能够起到作用
Destiny will work.
一定会的
It has to.
不会的 不可能起作用
No, it won't work.
地核已经出现异常
If you fire that thing again
你再发射那东西  你会毁了地核
with the core already stalled, it'll terminally destabilize it.
没错  我们要冒很大的风险
Yes, granted-- there is a marginal risk involved,
但是事情已经到了这个地步
but given the circumstances,
我想我们已经别无选择
I hardly see that there's an alternative.
不  辛斯基  听我说
No, Zimsky, listen to me.
地球上的每座火山都会爆发
Every volcano on the planet will blow.
那时的地震足够把任何东西撕成碎片
There'll be earthquakes big enough to rip us to pieces.
-凯斯博士  -什么
-Dr. Keyes. -What?
现在只有这个办法了
I'm afraid it's all we've got.
现在总统已经下达了命令
Now, I have orders from the president.
回来吧 维吉尔号
Come home, Virgil.
我们要执行B计划了
We go to plan B.
那么为什么不试试C计划
Well, what about plan C?
什么
What? What?
C计划
Well, plan C.
我们接着干
We continue on.
重新让地核活动起来
We restart the core... somehow.
如果你发射“命运”  我们就不干了
We don't do it, you fire Destiny.
我没有时间等你们撤退
I can't wait for you to get out of there.
那么就先等等  如果我们失败了再发射
Then don't. We fail, fire Destiny.
这太可笑了吧
Oh, come on! That's ridiculous!
我们有什么选择吗
What choice do we have,
-辛斯基  -你在开玩笑吗
-Zimsky? -Are you kidding me?
如果他们现在发射那东西
If they set that thing off,
冲击波会把我们撕碎
the shock waves will wipe us out!
如果我们现在就撤  也许还能回的去
We'll be lucky to get back if we turn back right now!
维吉尔号  给我听着  我们必须发射“命运”
Virgil, I'm telling you right now, we will fire Destiny,
并且我们会尽快发射
and we need to do so as quickly as possible,
如果你还不赶快回来
and if you're still there,
你们就完了
you will be destroyed.
蕾贝卡
Rebecca?
请不要逼我这么做
Please don't make me have to do this.
C计划
Plan C.
该下决定了  指挥官
It's your call, Commander.
少数服从多数
Majority decision.
我们继续
We're going in.
对不起  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
什么  你们这些傻瓜疯了吗
Oh, come on, you're a bunch of suicidal morons!
你怎么了
What are you, crazy?
C计划  重新启动地核
Plan C? Restart the core "somehow"?
真是个好主意
Oh, that's a great idea!
你们真是才华横溢
That's a brilliant idea!
真难以置信
I can't believe I'm stuck
这么一艘破船  你们这一群疯子
in this floating septic tank with you lunatics!
你们是没什么可失去的
You may have nothing to lose.
你们什么都没有
You may have nothing to lose!
You may have nothing to lose
但是我还不想死
but I have my life to lose,
非常感谢  你们赶快给我醒过来
thank you very much while you're up!
好好想想
Now turn it around!
他让我们回去  那么我们回去好了
He told us to go back and we're going back!
你想做英雄吗  你想做烈士
Why? You want to be a hero? You want to be a martyr?
你想干什么  你已经疯了
What do you want to be? You're out of your mind!
好好想想  谢谢
Thank you! Turn it around!
-不  -辛斯基
-No! -Zimsky.
闭嘴
You, shut up!
这艘船一点都不愚蠢
It's not a stupid ship.
很抱歉
I had to.
以前也发生过这种事情
It had to happen sometime.
报告情况  怎么回事
Status! What is that?
这个磁场监控站
It's the EM monitoring station.
负责监控
It's the one that
磁场的状态
tracks EM pulses.
我的天哪
God, no.
怎么回事  “老鼠”先生
Just talk, Mr. Rat.
不
No.
他们干得不错
That's a good boy.
还记得约书亚说的那些
Remember those invisible microwaves
微冲击波吗
that Josh was talking about?
它们已经漏进来了
Well, they just found a hole.
已侦测电磁摧毁处
不是  这里又塞车了
No, it's a parking lot out here...
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
现在
And now with this
重大灾难新闻报道
horrific breaking news,
旧金山遭遇了大规模自然灾害
we go live to San Francisco, where Leo Jacks has the story.
没错  克莱尔  确实难以置信
Yes, Claire, it's hard to believe
今天半个旧金山已经毁了
that half of San Francisco is in ruins today
完全毁灭  而我们对此无计可施
following the most devastating and the most baffling
回溯我们的过去
event in our nation's history.
情况还从来没有这么糟过
It's-it's a horrific situation here.
数千人死亡
Thousands are dead.
更多的人失踪
Many are missing.
看看这些旅馆  医院
It's-it's hotels, hospitals.
开启能源监视系统
Bring up the power grid.
整个西海岸线都处于危险中
The whole West Coast is out.
如果洛杉矶山脉爆发
That means we're going to have to suck up just about every drop
我们对那些岩浆和高温气体束手无策
of juice east of the Rockies
准备发射“命运”
to fire Destiny.
磁场再次异常  我们的能源快要不够了
Another EM spike, we're not going to have enough power.
将军  你必须多给他们点时间
General, you have got to give them more time.
已经没有时间了
There is no more time.
将军  准备完毕
Colonel, call Destiny.
我要向国防部提交
I am launching a formal complaint
正式的抗议书了
against you with the Department of Defense.
“老鼠”呼叫约书亚
Rat to Josh.
继续“老鼠”
Go, Rat.
这是你们需要的电磁场区域资料
here's the EM Field data that you're primed for.
多谢  “老鼠”
Digging that, Rat.
就是它
Primed for.
关键性数据
Prime numbers
1  2  3  5
one, two, three, five,
7  11  13  17
seven, eleven, thirteen, seventeen...
我不喜欢“命运”  我可以帮忙吗
我们需要时间  找到“命运”  延迟它的发射
我们开始吧
Here we go.
命运计划  阿拉斯加
詹姆斯
James.
长官
Yes, sir.
是  长官
开始吧  伙计们
Here we go, folks.
这次它终于工作了
Okay, this time it's going to work.
没错  就这样  继续  继续
Here you go... beautiful. Yeah, mm-hmm.
很好
Come on, baby.
继续  我还想再看一次天空
Come on, Daddy wants to see the sky again.
好  好  我们再来一次
Okay, okay, okay. Let's try again.
注意  扭矩是R
Your torque is R,
穿过F点
cross F...
你的R点太小了  约书亚
No, your R is too small, Josh.
没错
Right.
等等
Wait, hold on.
你在笑什么
What are you laughing at?
我还有其他几百个精英
No, I mean, it took me and 400 of the world's smartest people
设计了A计划
to come up with the first plan.
你想帮忙吗
You want to help?
不  我只想掉头回家
No. I want to turn around and go home.
这是不可能的
It's not going to happen.
那么  我们都会死
Well, then we're going to die.
没错
True.
你想想
All right, look,
-让我们从这个正方形开始 -好的
-let's start from square one. -Okay.
我们从这个正方形开始
Let's start from square one.
这部分与密度的关系十分密切
The bulk modules-- depends on density.
你的扭矩是R  穿过F点
Your torque is R cross F,
但是你要先对体积求积分
but you have to integrate volume...
但是  这里  看看  这里
But here, here... just consider this.
现在  我们
Now, we got this...
好的  穿过F点
Okay, now, R cross F,
我们已经把派值考虑进去了
we're putting in pi. What's V?
看在上帝的份上
Oh, for God's sake!
很好  让我再打他一顿
All right. I'm hitting him again.
不  不
No, no, no!
布雷兹  不  你瞧  我有个意见
Braz, no, look, I have a theory.
有兴趣听吗
Are you interested?
我们都听着
Yes. We're interested.
先让我抽只烟  然后听我说
Then let me smoke a cigarette, and I'll tell you.
感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
很好  你瞧
All right, fine, look.
我们需要冲击波产生干涉式反应  对吧
Look, we have to use wave interference, okay?
一次爆炸是不能产生这样效果的
Because one explosion won't do it.
试想一下池塘里面得石头
Think about stones in a pond.
把一块大石头扔进池塘
You drop a large stone into a pond,
有很多水滴会飞溅起来
you get a big splash,
然后就结束了
and then that's it, it's over.
但是如果扔一块小石头进去  等到水波慢慢稀疏
But drop a smaller stone, wait until the ripples weaken
然后再扔进去一块小石头
and drop another and another, and another, and fluid dynamics 101.
水波的能量将以几何级数的速度增长
The ripples reinforce each other in geometric progression.
整体大于局部之和
Hm, the whole bigger than the sum of the parts.
这样我们可以将五个
Then we'll have five
200兆吨级的炸弹
200 megaton explosions...
分别进行引爆
Instead of one big bang.
用电线短路方法起动核仪器
So, we hot-wire the nukes.
没错
Yes.
代替一次大爆炸
And as one does,
我们把这些炸弹精确地
we seed them through the core...
放到地核里面
at locations that have to be accurate to the inch.
然后按照预定的顺序引爆
We detonate them in a sequence that has to be accurate to the millisecond...
这将是历史上规模最大的一次核爆
then we outrun the biggest nuclear shock wave in history.
没错
Right.
是的
Yeah.
我想这应该是很简单的
I mean, that should be fairly simple.
“命运”准备完毕
Destiny now should be diverting to the central.
最后一次校正
Final calibration
所有发射系统
on both transmission systems...
能源资料部
无法进入
快点
Come on.
切断
Cut the... cut the rouge.
电路上方的红色电线
The red wire above the circuit.
好的  好的
Okay. Okay.
不对  等等
No, no, wait, hold it!
对不起  应该是电路下方的红色电线
I'm sorry, cut it below.
快点
Please...
A区  B区
Extensions A, B.
-准备  -能量检查
-Here we go. -F, check.
将反应堆的能量加到15
Increase power to reactors ten through 15
已经准备好了
We're almost there, folks.
限制
42小时  深度2600英里
伙计们  我们已经接近里核了
Okay, guys we're closing on the inner core.
核弹已经准备好了
The nukes are ready. Timers are on.
很好  准备投弹
Great. Let's start dropping them.
但是这里的压力太大了  炸弹受不了
No. The bombs are not built for these pressures.
所以这些炸弹外面都有保护层
That's why they were in that pod.
如果你现在投弹
If you send them out now...
他们立刻就会爆炸
out of that casing, they'll be crushed instantly.
那么我们有D计划吗
I'm assuming we have a Plan D.
D计划就是我们用维吉尔本身做核弹的外壳
Plan D is Virgil's compartments.
我们把核弹
We put a nuke in
分别放置好
each section of Virgil
然后每次去掉一个保护层
and then eject the individual sections one at a time.
它们应该能够坚持一段时间
They should stay intact long enough for the nuke to go off.
怎么了
What?
但是在一切正常的情况下  维吉尔号不会自动脱落的
Virgil's not designed to eject undamaged compartments.
但是总有一个控制机构
Okay, these are the ejection mechanisms
来控制各部分的动作
holding each compartment in place.
这些部分就被一个“关键点”联接着
They're all connected by one master hydraulic gear.
就好像是钥匙圈一样
Kind of like keys on a key ring.
我们要做的 就是用钥匙打开它
What we have to do, we have to unlock the piston.
这样所有的部分就会散开
That will release the compartments
这样炸弹就可以被引爆了
so the bombs can be jettisoned.
那么这个“关键点”在哪里
Where's the master gear?
就在引擎喷口附近
In the crawl space we used to get out earlier.
它怎么在那里
Well, what the hell is it doing there?
我只用了三个月的时间来建造这艘船
I built the ship in three damn months.
我不是故意怠工
I didn't think I'd be
对不起
intentionally sabotaging it. I'm sorry!
那么我们有一个人必须去了
So one of us has to go in there.
没错
Correct.
那里的温度有9000多度
Into the crawl space that has core fluid at 9, 000 degrees.
没错
Yes.
你能用液化氮把那里淹没吗
Can you flush it with liquid nitrogen?
我们的液化氮不够了
We don't have enough at this point.
9000度
9, 000 degrees.
但是我们的工作服只能抵挡
And our suits are built to withstand...?
4500度
Half that, probably.
很错  只有一半
Right. Half that.
所以你的意思是
So what you're saying is
无论谁去那里  肯定是回不来了
whoever goes into that crawl space, is not coming back.
我们一起
Together.
好的
Yes, thank you.
稍等
Wait.
-我数三下  -好的
-On three. -Okay.
1  2  3
One... two... three.
看来我最好去准备准备
Well, I better go on, get myself ready.
不  布雷兹  等一下
No, Braz, wait.
布雷兹  等一下
No, Braz, no wait. Excuse me.
等等  我能不能看看
Just a moment, may I see that?
-不行  -让我看看
-No. -May l?
行吗
May l?
好吧
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
小戏法
Magic.
布雷兹  这三根线的长度相等
I mean, Braz, three straws of equal length.
我说  这太孩子气了
I mean, this is childish.
我们再来一次
Let's do it again.
用不着了
No, we will not do it again.
我想你一定很高兴吧
I thought you'd be happy.
不  但是你也
No. Not at the expense
不应该这样做
of you making us look like fools.
他是对的  你为什么要抢着去做英雄
He's right. Why do you get dibs on being the hero?
因为这是我的船
Because it's my damn ship.
这就足够了吗
Oh, that makes perfect sense.
你知道吗  20年来  除了维吉尔号我一无所有
Look, for 20 years, I've done nothing but Virgil. 20 years.
维吉尔号是我的唯一
Virgil belongs to me,
无论如何我不能让它毁坏
and I will not let her fail.
我不允许
I will not.
如果你想知道这艘船对我
Now if you want to know what's worth dying for
来说多重要
this ship.
为了保全它
Building it instead of imagining it.
我宁愿用我的血去保卫它
If Virgil needs more blood, it will be my blood.
现在我要去
Now I am going to go
准备了
and get ready.
准备好了
Good to go.
小贝
Beck.
约书亚
Josh.
你造了一艘好船  布雷兹
It's a hell of a boat you built, Braz.
能认识你们我很荣幸
I am really proud to have known you guys.
谢谢
Thank you.
布雷兹
Braz.
爱德华
Edward.
怎么了  康拉德
Yes, Conrad?
你是对的
You're right.
这是你的船
It is your ship.
但是现在它是我们的
But I wish to God it had been ours.
快要打开密封门了
The chamber's sealed, Beck.
准备
Ready.
打开舱门
Open the hatch.
挺住  布雷兹
Hang on, Braz.
挺住
Come on, hang on.
手动解体系统启动
Manual override is complete!
布雷兹  我们还能把你弄出来
Braz, we can still get you out of there.
走  你们走吧  打开推进器
No... start... start the impeller.
不
No.
我们还有事情要做
We got a job to do.
开始吧
Let's do it.
来吧
Let's go.
磁防护系统启动完毕
Magnetic shielding systems are up.
能量85%
Power level's 85%.
反应堆能量提高到10
Increase power to Reactor 10.
所有人员撤离
All personnel should be clear.
禁止进入
天哪
Oh, God!
啊  对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
好了  行了
Okay, she's down.
接近第一投放点
Approaching the first drop-off point.
我们要加速了  伙计们
We got to be accurate to the second here, boys.
3-5分钟内投放第二枚
And drop in three-five seconds.
计时器启动
And... timer on.
拉出来
Pull it.
准备
Clear... and...
投放
ejecting.
好的  准备启动
All right. Initiate firing sequence.
长官
Sir...
这是我们最后的任务了  史迪克
It's our last shot, Stick.
去你的
Damn you.
去我的  太晚了
Damn me? Too late.
10  9  8
Ten, nine, eight...
这是什么
What's that?
命运计划中央控制
就是你
Gotcha!
4  3  2
...four, three, two...
有人把能源全部转移了
Someone's diverted our energy.
这些能源都跑哪去了
Where the hell's it gone?!
看起来好像是
It looks like...
兔子岛
Coney lsland.
你们的功夫还差点
Your Kung Fu is not strong.
把能源转移回来需要多长时间
Well, how long will it take to get it back online?
那么  尽快！
Well, then get to it!
将军
Oh, hey, General.
有什么事吗
Is there something I can do for you?
计时器启动
Timer on.
准备
Clear...
分离！
ejecting.
分离
Ejecting.
拉出来
Pull it.
好的
All right.
准备把最后一块  200兆吨的石头扔进池塘
Let's go throw our last little 200 megaton stone in the pond.
不知道这些核弹激起的波纹是什么样的
I always wanted to make a splash in nuclear physics.
你知道这些能量的传播方式
You know, that energy propagation stuff
你是说
you were talking about...
没错  大学物理里面就讲过
Oh, that was high school physics.
对  但是仍然不够准确
Yeah, it's not exactly...
我只是根据地核的MRI定律计算的
I just took the wavelengths from the core fluidoff the MRl readings.
-对  然后乘以800  -600
-Yeah, and multiplied by 800... -600
确定但你补充了MRI偏压
Surely you compensated for the MRl bias.
快重新设定定时器
We got to reset the timers!
重新定时  不  没用的
Reset the timers! No! It just won't work.
不是定时器的问题  它本身就不够
It's not the timers! This is not enough!
什么不够
What's not enough?
这枚核弹的力量还不足以
The last bomb is not enough.
完成整个冲击波链
T o complete the wave form.
对  最后一枚炸弹的爆炸力必须增加30%
Yeah. No. The last bomb has to be 30% larger.
大约需要六到七公斤的钚
That's six or seven pounds of plutonium.
见鬼  我们哪有这么多的钚
Where are we going to get six or seven pounds of plutonium?
小心  船体受到突发
Guys, we got hit
力量的冲击
by an energy flare.
分离过程无法中止
I can't keep us on course.
喷射仓将在50秒种后开启
Ejecting compartment in 50 seconds.
不  小贝  等等  用力推
No, Beck! No, wait! No! Push it!
你也推
You push it!
你们怎么了  我听不到你们了
Come on, guys, I can't hear you.
它压在我的肩膀上了
It's got my shoulder!
推
Push!
嗨
Guys!
好了吗
Clear!
快从喷射仓里面出来  你们在干什么
Clear the compartment! What are you doing?
刚才的振动好像把通讯器弄坏了
I think the flare has knocked the Coms out.
不行  推不动  约书亚  推不动
I can't get it, Josh. I can't get it.
快走
Go...
不行
I can't.
好的
Okay.
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
喷射仓就要开启了
I'm correcting course. Now!
辛斯基
Zimsky!
不
No!
用力推
Push it!
喷射仓将在10秒种之内开启
Ejecting compartment in ten seconds.
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
约书亚  快走  快走
Josh, go! Go! Go!
出去
Get out! Get out!
快给我出去  现在
Now! Get out! Now! Get out! Go!
约书亚
Josh.
用反应堆的
For the last bomb, to make it larger...
钚环来提高核弹的威力
use the fuel rods from the react...
分离
Ejecting.
我必须要
I got to get...
必须去
I got to...
小贝
Beck.
小贝  听到了吗
Beck, can you hear me?
小贝  如果你还有什么好主意  趁现在赶快告诉我
Beck, if you have any better ideas, you tell me now.
我们只有三分钟来调整下一枚核弹
We've only got three minutes to eject this one.
小贝
Beck!
我听不到你们
Come on, guys. I can't hear you.
小贝
Beck.
辐射程度
温度
警告
约书亚  过来
Josh, come on.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
怎么样
能帮我摘掉手套吗
Will you take my gloves off?
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
帮帮忙
Please.
我必须这么做
I had to build the blast.
对不起
I'm sorry.
坚持住  我去拿点
Hold on, let me get...
不  留在这
No. Stay here for one second.
我刚才想告诉你
I was trying to call you.
我知道通讯器坏了
I know the Coms were down.
是的
Right.
我知道你做了什么
I know what you did.
我们已经没有足够的能量
We don't have enough energy...
我知道
I know.
回去了
...to get back.
你做得很好
You did good.
如果是我  我也会这么做
I would've done the same thing.
辛斯基呢
Where's Zimsky?
过来
Come here.
你做得很好
You did good.
做的好
一分钟后爆炸
One minute to the first detonation.
12分钟后冲击波将击中我们
And 12 until the blast hits us.
希望我们能窒息而死
I was hoping we'd suffocate to death first.
温度危急
小贝
Beck.
小贝  小贝
Beck, Beck.
如果我能让
What could you do
推进器转起来  你能把我们弄出去吗
if I got you enough power to fire the impeller?
激光钻头可能不行  但是我可以启动推进器
Maybe not the laser but the impeller.
什么  能量从哪来呢
What? From where?
地核的热量
The heat of the core.
足足9000度的高温
It's 9, 000 degrees.
我们可以把热量转为我们需要的能源
Unobtainium converts heat to energy.
这艘船就象是一块太阳能电池
So this whole damn ship is like a big, old solar panel.
来  我需要你的帮助
Come on, I need your help.
已经有两枚核弹爆炸了
Number two's going!
只有在无限的未知中
For here in the great infinite unknowable...
人们才能知道最重要的事情是什么
man can come to know the most important thing of all
他自己
himself.
他能知道
He can understand...
我他妈的到底在做什么
What the fuck am I doing?
起作用了
We've got full rotation!
正常运转了
It's turning!
太好了
All right!
快点  小贝  在哪里
Come on, Beck, where is it?
快点
Come on. Come on, hurry up.
这是最后一个吗
Is that the last one?
是的
Yeah.
再等几秒钟
Give it a couple seconds.
启动了
It worked!
准备感受力量吧
Get ready to pull a few G's.
船速420节
420 knots.
这才像布雷兹的船
Now, this is more like it.
440节
440.
怎么回事  这里也会有地震
So, Rat, what's the center of this quake?
到处都是
It's everywhere!
这是巨大冲击波的结果
It's one giant shock wave!
这颗星球在给它自己加热
The planet's healing itself.
我们就要到家了 第三次回家
At this speed, we're going to be home in a third of the time.
只要我们能够冲过
As long as we can surf
这些岩浆  我们就安全了
these magma flows, we'll be okay.
上帝保佑  千万不要冲进死路
Let's just pray we don't run into any dead ends,
或者丢失导航信号
or we're going to miss those lasers.
走那边
Okay, navigator, which way?
我想左边是最好的
We've got greater fluid density on the left.
跟着岩浆的流向走好了
Go with the flow.
16小时后
比尔  他们在向哪里开
Bill, where are they headed?
他们好像在夏威夷
Looks like she found a space between
附近找到了一条出路
some tectonic plates somewhere near Hawaii.
约书亚
Josh...
我们已经接近地表了
They're closing in on us too fast.
我不知道我能不能
I don't know if I can...
别担心
Hey, you got it.
讯号中断
找不到他们了  史迪克  我
Um... w-we lost them, Stick, and I...
四小时后
我们的能源呢
Where'd our power go?
我们的能源来自地核的热量
Well, we're powered by the heat.
这里太冷了
It's stone cold down here.
想想好的一面
Look on the bright side.
起码我们不会活活被热死
At least we're not going to boil to death.
你总是能看到积极的一面吗
You always look on the bright side?
没错
Always.
好吧  再想想
Okay, let's assess
通讯装备已经不能用了
We've got no communications,
现在我们应该在海面下800英尺
we're probably 800 feet down,
但也可能是800英里
but we might as well be 800 miles.
我们对外界的情况一无所知
We're in an Unobtainium
声呐系统也不能直接找到我们
cigar tube with the sonar signature of a rock.
我们得想点办法让声纳能听到我们
We've got just enough power to make the ultrasonics burp,
但是好像已经
but no one's listening
没有人用这些频率了
on those frequencies anyway, and...
甚至没人知道我们还活着
nobody even knows we're alive.
好吧
Okay.
给我一分钟
Give me a minute on this one.
夏威夷海岸
完全没希望
This is hopeless.
将军  我们已经离得这么近了
Come on, General, we've got to be getting close.
我们不能
We can't...
“老鼠”先生  就算他们还活着
Mr. Rat, even if they were still alive,
他们也没办法和我们取得联系
there's no way they could contact us.
这里是舰桥
Bridge.
船长  我们的潜艇扫描到一些东西
Skipper, Combat relays that our sub has something on the sonar.
在哪里
Where do they think?
比尔  再听一下
Bill, put it up on the hydrophone.
鲸鱼  先生
Whales, sir.
这些鲸鱼本来不应该在这里出现
They're a long way off their usual path,
不过这也不是什么不可思议的事情
but that's not uncommon since that, uh...
这应该怎么称呼
what are they calling it?
轨道漂移
Orbital wobble?
是的  他们就是这么称呼
Yeah, that's what they call it.
那么  谢谢你  船长
Well, thank you very much, Captain,
我想我们的任务已经结束了
but I think we're done here.
将军
General.
J.O.  我是船长
J.O., this is the captain.
行动中止
Stand down from SAR Operations.
是鲸  是鲸
It's whales! It's whales!
将军
Hey! General!
史迪克
Stick!
就是鲸
It's whales!
鲸也能发出超声波
The ultrasonics!
它们正在为维吉尔号发信号
They're singing to them!
你要找到那些鲸鱼
You gotta find the whales!
Alpha X  这是NE610
Alpha X Ray, this is November Echo six one zero.
我换一下位置
I'm changing...
等等  我已经看到那些鲸鱼了
Hold on, I'm seeing those whales now.
真是一场精彩的水戏
Okay, ball's in the water.
这些鲸鱼在围着什么东西不停的旋转
This is neat. Those whales are circling something.
稍等  听
Hold on, hold on.
有一组特别强烈的回声
We have a strong echo here.
深度800英尺
Depth, 800 feet.
那里一定有东西
There-there's something down there.
一定有东西沉在那里了
There's definitely something down there.
我告诉过你  这些超声波一定有用
I told you pulsing the ultrasonics would work.
你从来没有感到过累吗
Do you ever get tired of being right?
是的
Yes.
接下来你要做什么
So what's next for you?
舒舒服服洗个澡
A shower.
然后我想回NASA
Then back to NASA, I guess.
你呢
You?
猛吃一顿意大利香肠皮萨  加上胡椒粉和圆葱
Deep-dish pepperoni pizza, green peppers, onions,
当然还要有蘑菇  然后好好洗个澡  回我的学校去
extra mushrooms-- then a shower and then back to the classroom.
NASA总算是找到一些好人
NASA could use a few good men, you know.
没错
Yeah.
不过  我的新学生可惨了
Unfortunately, so could my freshmen geophysics students.
你知道什么事情让我气愤
You know what makes me really, really angry?
鲍勃  赛吉  布雷兹  辛斯基
Bob, Serge, Braz, Zimsky...
没有人会知道他们做了什么  他们为什么去死
no one's going to ever know what they did or why they died.
除非
Unless...
莫名其妙的这些事情就泄露了
it all got out somehow.
真是莫名其妙
That's unthinkable.
没错
Yeah.
加州  一周后
网路咖啡馆
机密
功夫
下载…老鼠网路
好  继续
Okay, here we go.
资料读取中
很好
Sweet.
已读取
档名  无名英雄
我们终于了解到  我们的地球是因为
It is now emerging that the world owes its survival
这六个不同寻常  的人才得以脱离为难
to the heroism of six remarkable individuals
航天飞机的指挥官  罗伯特·艾弗森
Shuttle Commander Robert lverson, ...
法国科学家赛吉博士…
French Scientist, Dr. Serge...
…是太空总署的船长  宇航员鲍勃·艾弗森博士
was captained by NASA astronaut Dr. Bob lverson.
爱德华·布雷兹是一个如此
Edward Brazzleton is a name so...
康拉德·辛斯基博士的  英勇值得我们每个人永远怀念
Dr. Conrad Zimsky will be best remembered...
今天的议会上
On Capitol Hill today,
每个人都在问同样的问题
everyone's asking the same question
“命运”计划到底是什么
What is Project Destiny?
“命运”来临了
Destiny, meet world.
世界看到了“命运”
World, meet Destiny.
剧终
The End